Hello everyone. Can everyone hear me?
Um,
okay.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. We have I'm
trying to get rid of this um
video.
Ah, here we go.
That's me.
Good evening everyone or morning in
regarding where you are. Uh do you have
sounds now? Can you hear me perfectly?
Yes. Hello. Yes, everyone. Oh, that's a
lot of Yes. Um so, thank you very much
for being here tonight. It's going to be
an amazing webinar. Um I think because
there is a knowledge here that I have
never disclosed before.
So you're the lucky ones.
And um this knowledge I have it from two
sources.
my
endless and regular conversations with
Prince Ia, my old friend and also with
some elder called the sea. Cali, the
Cula are interdimensional beings. They
live in another universe and some of
them know a lot about things and it was
interesting also to have their
perspective and also through what I have
seen on board the Nibiru ship in the Mad
Kahal library. So all of these combined
I am bringing to you tonight
what is time?
Time,
space, and consciousness
are the three
variables of creation.
From time, space and consciousness
grows the totality of all that is.
Time, space, and consciousness. They are
built upon the same structure,
one single structure,
what you call the flower of life.
I prepared some transparent
um things. I I I've been drawing drawing
this. So I went through this drawing
this for you. It wasn't easy
on the plexiglass. So that's a flower of
life. Okay, that you know that it's been
present in all the ancient temples of
humanity. It's been kept as a knowledge
as a key uh from uh by the ancients
and for you to come to this day and to
show you the secret of the universe.
This is the creation. This is the
structure the latis of the creation.
So before going further in what is
exactly this thing
um I want to
address a warning about of course
misinformation counter disclosure
counter information all the time this is
carved painted sculpted
everywhere around the world from
memorial times from pre pre younger das
Like for abidos for instance,
China,
Europe, everywhere, everywhere,
everywhere, everywhere.
Because this is the greatest secret.
We could say this is God.
the counter intelligence and the enemies
of humanity, the leil faction, they try
to
to to
take you away from this knowledge.
So
how to take people away from a knowledge
when this knowledge is carved, sculpted
and painted in the old temples of
humanity?
Well, by uh creating a counternarrative
that will discredit it. That's what they
do. They they've been doing that all
along. Creating counternarratives to
hijack the reality and make it look as
in fact it is the the lie.
There's a narrative that's been created
that was very well done but very easy to
to expose. Uh it's the narrative of the
dise.
So of course because this is the latis
of creation. This is life. This is
source. This is creator. This is how the
universe is structured. Um it was
necessary uh by the enemy to uh
discredit it saying oh that's the not
the flower of death. They called it a
daisy of death and they invented another
structure.
Um
yes, this is a it is a funny nonsense
because this I I'm I'm going to tell you
um
this is this been uh this narrative this
um scop has been uh carried on by a lady
called Ashayana Dean and um it's been
also uh taken over after that by another
lady Mrs. Renee,
um
this when you go into these uh
um CIA uh created material, the daisy of
death, you you very quickly see their
ways of doing and there are publications
from documents from the CIA and I know
Dan Willis will find the right link and
the right document because he's here in
the chat
that say that He'll find the you'll find
the right quote. But this documents I
couldn't find it, but I read it
somewhere. The CIA said um to
there's a tactic to fit um a lie. It's
that to make it complicate. When you
make it complicate, the people will be
um will feel guilty or ashamed not to
understand. They will pretend to
understand it and they will conform to
everyone else even though they don't
understand it. And the material of ash
Yes, Dan. It's true. The material of
Ashayadin is done as such. It's a
compound of uh it's things taken from a
Jewish cabala. Some um um Middle Eastern
traditions and some um mystery schools
traditions.
It's all a mikmack. You have also names
of angels and uh it's a lot of um abraic
things in it. It's a mish mash of a lot
of things that people can find reference
to existing traditions but it's all
mixed together. So uh to make you feel
like oh my god this is so complicated it
must be true. Spoiler alert,
the truth is simple
because it speaks to your heart, your
consciousness, and you know, you
understand it straight away.
This is the truth.
This is the flower of life. This is the
rose of knowledge, the sacred rose of
the alchemist.
Now
and that said
um when you look at this and you see all
the the circles in fact all the circles
are not flat this is a representation
uh two dimensional but in fact it's
round it's bubble universe it's spheres
well more or less spheres
um and these lines are these these lines
are see them in volume. They are
bubbles.
Each one is a universe. So that's a
blueprint. Okay? It's a blueprint of
creation. It's not
strictly like this because creation is
moving. It's a continuous flow.
So
the this bubble universe, I'm going to
show you something. Um,
if if you follow the the the the
take a pen. Okay, I'm going to do that.
Um,
like this.
Take a pen. Have a red here. Red.
Okay.
Not on it. The other side. Yes. I'm
going to try to do this.
No, I'm going to do it like this. Sorry.
First time I'm doing this. Okay. I don't
know if you see that.
If No. Okay. I'm going to this side.
Okay.
These bubbles overlap. You see the
overlap? Okay. You see the overlap?
If you take
a line and you go like this, you change
universe. You travel through the
universe.
You can kind of make a route. Okay.
You Oh, you can't find it. No, it's not
working. You have a glyph.
What I've just done, if I go over with
my red pen,
you have a glyph,
you see?
And these glyphs are the
interdimensional keys to go from a
universe to another.
So um
I try to make it simple with that.
It's you are drawing the pathways
between the universes.
Okay. You create a route and um
it it's
it's it's that that goes from one point
to the other of the great design but not
flat you know in volume. So these glyphs
are what we call interdimensional keys.
Um you really must see with your mind
that this is not a flat okay it's
multi-dimensional holographic construct.
So
these bubble universes
they
creation comes from for instance the
center and it grows. It grows and grows
and the universe as they grow
they get away from the center and they
become more wobbly and more they have
their own growth their own
expansion.
and sometimes overlap with others and
sometimes only for a while.
And a universe will grow
will be bigger um when it has
more densities. The scale of densities
is higher
longer the longer octave. the song of
that universe is a longer octave.
So, um,
now
where does that to show you the universe
how it is? That's the body of creation.
The body of of creator.
That's what the creator looks like.
And how and where does your journey
comes into the p picture?
Well, we could say at the center of this
design, but the center is everywhere.
Source
creator is
her creation.
Thorhan says her, so I say her as well.
And it's I mean Ia says her. They all
say her because it's a a matrix. It's a
womb of creation.
So a consciousness
all the individual individualized
consciousness that populate all of
creations
are fractal
from the heart of one consciousness.
Okay.
We are in the beginning
a very small sprout from the soul of the
creator. You imagine
that there is a oneness of consciousness
like a reservoir of consciousness
something that has no limit of space and
no limit of time. And from this big
reservoir of consciousness
there are offshoots constantly
constantly it just shoots off
consc consciousness and fractals of
itself fractals of itself.
I spoke a lot about this in my book the
cedars
where I showed me all of this and the
nine as well. So you can have this this
this experience as well. we can find it.
So as we grow, we develop individualized
awareness as needed for creator to
experience
through this fractal of shoots of itself
or herself that it sends out.
Some souls even choose to experience
not just one universe but several
different universes.
When we fractal
from the one creator,
as long as we we do not join any
planetary evolutionary biometrics
and as long as we only choose to observe
worlds on our journey, we remain as a
non-incarnated plasmic consciousness
fully aware of who we are.
We can choose to remain in this state
for a while or forever
at the start or at the end of our
journey. And we'll come back to that.
For once we begin incarnation,
we forget. We are stuck to complete the
whole cycle.
We are stuck in the chosen planetary
matrix.
I am going to go over this uh planetary
matrix um
um thing again. I've been explaining
this in my last webinar on consciousness
but um so your consciousness is an
embryo of consciousness and an an a
little thing that is barely aware of
them itself. It shoots off into space
and there you are
an an egg of of all possibilities.
And in that this little blob, plasmic
blob, it's you and it's in into space.
And
you are aiming for a planet, a world
where your consciousness will anchor and
incarnate.
in the most simple of
life forms and from there start the
cycle of incarnations through all the
life forms of this planet. all the
rains, not all the life forms, but the
minerals, vegetital,
water, animals, insect until the the
most evolved
um creature on that planet can be human,
can be anything else.
As long as you are going through these
cycles of incarnation,
you
are on a journey to remember who you
are.
And this is creator experiencing
evolution
through you.
And once ex evolution this experience of
evolution has completed that you've
reached the highest
life form the highest stage of life form
on that planet.
Creator through experience will have
grown,
nourished itself or herself from
not really your experience but
its experience through your journey.
Remember you are a fractal of it. You
are it and it is you.
And when
at the end of all the cycles you are
ready to go embark for the next step of
this journey
you you can incarnate in another world
another planet but not as
going back again from the beginning
because that won't be your home your
planetary biometric. You have only one
home, the planetary biometrics in which
your soul, your consciousness has grown
and developed from embryo to adult
consciousness. But once you've completed
these cycles,
you are ready to leave home. If you want
to, you can stay there and reincarnate
all the time on your planet because you
like it. It's fine and it's your
experience. You can go and incarnate on
then on another planet as the highest
life form.
These are the star seeds or the envoys
who choose to incarnate
to come to earth through incarnation not
through a stasis pod or we're going to
talk about the stasis pod later.
There are two ways of being an envoy,
right? Through putting your body in
stasis, getting out of it, and
incarnating into an embryo. But also,
you have the choice to die on your home
world and follow the natural universal
cycle of incarnation and leave your
planetary biometrics for good. You can
come back, of course, but that's the
cycle. So
a star seed or envoy
will be someone who can incarnate on
another world by two methods. putting
their body in stasis and going back to
their body once the incarnation is over
or dying on their home world and well
completing their last life and moving on
to the the incarnation etheric
biometrics to another world and stay
there
or move afterwards whatever come home if
they want to. So you see the difference.
But anyway to do to go through the
the whole process you need to be at the
later stage of your incarnation when on
your planet when you decide to go by
death and rebirth.
When you go in a stasis spod
uh it is different.
You are not
obliged to have completed all your
incarnations on your home world.
You just do a job and you come back and
you will finish your cycle.
Okay, that's two different ways to be a
star seed. So that was good to remind uh
to keep in mind.
Now
we are uh coming into the
the heat of the subject.
Time is not linear.
While you are incarnated into this
terran avatar,
your other incarnations
live too.
Now I'm going to ask you to
get out of the linear thinking
and just for a moment
try to not judge not calculate not try
to relate to what you are experiencing
here.
Just allow your consciousness and your
mind to absorb
this
and you will understand
in a little moment.
So while you are here, your other
incarnations live to in the past and in
the future because time is not linear.
You can communicate with them.
These are not different timelines.
No, there is only one and unique eternal
time
and it is not linear.
It is spherical.
Time exists as a whole
at once.
The word time line exists only regarding
linear time.
When you are incarnated on a planet with
its rotation cycle,
its orbit around its star
and of course of its star around the
galactic center in 250 million years.
You experience time as linear when you
are bound by gravity.
Time in the absolute is not a line.
It's a field.
And there is only one
unique spherical time field
eternity in one moment.
Same
as there is only one infinite space.
Infinity in one space
and one infinite
creator consciousness.
The three
constants of the universe,
time,
space, consciousness,
eternity, infinity,
oneness,
time, eternity, space, infinity,
consciousness, oneness.
This is creator. This is creation.
Are you right?
That is what incarn that is um what
incarnated beings subject to gravity.
That's why they have difficulty to
comprehend.
You need to extract your mind from
linear thinking. This happens when you
incarnate in a biometric as I said but
you know this you lose this
comprehension of time of this of the
time field because you switch into a
planetary linear time gravity orbital
time
orbital time.
But anyone is able to remember this. You
just have to snap out of gravitational
time.
project your consciousness out of your
body
through meditation for instance.
I know it's hard to extract your mind
from linear gravity but you can do it.
Now listen,
all the incarnations you have lived
are existing
simultaneously in the universal time
field because there is no linear time in
the absolute
but you cannot access them or interact
with them as long as you are in gravity
linear time.
It also explains the confusion
as to why people sometimes
believe that their soul is split into
different timelines
or other dimensional universes which is
an illusion.
It is a misperception.
linearity. The experience, the linear
linear experience of time
is um a perception,
not reality. It's a perception of
reality.
It would go against the natural laws of
creation to think that um a human soul
could split into subsouls to animate
different avatars at the same time.
This is not working.
But you know you your consciousness is
one
You cannot be many of your yourself in
the same present in the same time. But
I'm going to talk about uh
reincarnations a little bit further.
First I need to to uh precise that um
splitting of consciousness can be done
artificially. It's against the laws of
the universe against the laws of
creation but it unfortunately can be
done uh by technology.
uh but it never happens in the natural
laws of creation but when it's done by
by technology I mean the person is
suffering a lot a lot it's it's torment
it's it's it's not natural
so when you meet yourself who lived and
died on another world hundreds of
thousands of years ago
you meet yourself
as you were then as a whole complete
soul being just same as you are now.
This is you but this is also you.
If you are in linear time you can say
this was me in a previous life
in the linearity of time. But if you are
in the time field, out of incarnation,
out of gravity, you say, "Oh, that's
another that's me."
That's just me in another incarnation.
That has already happened,
but that is still there,
still existing.
It's complicated, but it is like this.
So um
you meet yourself as a whole and you are
not a fraction of each other but you are
two separate complete whole individuals
who are still the same person
regarding the spherical time field of
creation.
Our
soul journey is not as straight and uh
simple as we first imagined. Right?
In fact, uh it is anything but a
straight line.
Our soul journey
is a winding multi-dimensional roller
coaster in a spherical time field.
We come from and are made of source.
You are the image of God. Yes. Not the
body, the consciousness.
But as soon as we detach from it, from
her, we begin the journey back to the
source by experiencing everything there
is to experience in the creation field
of all existence.
And here you are.
You have woven family ties along the
way. Real true bonds that will last
forever.
You are
the only one of your kind
like everyone else is.
unique
linear
linear time is not a thing.
So all your incarnations coexist in the
same time field but there is only one
you.
The concept of multiple timelines is um
it's false because a timeline is an
illusion, a perception, a distortion of
our perception of time related to our
experience of gravity.
Absolute time is a field
in which every second coexist at the
same time.
Imagine that field
composed with myriads of tiny dots and
they all exist at the same time. But
this dot may be you when you were living
in I don't know Atlantis. And this dot
may be you now. And this dot is you in
the future on Mars or wherever else.
But they all exist at the same time.
It's a field. Okay.
Time is a quantum field.
There is no linearity in the absolute
time quantum field.
Past, present, and future coexist in the
time field.
So, we're going to get in the heat of
the subject now because we're not yet
there.
What happens if we interact with the
past event and change the present?
Now
if you make a mistake in one incarnation
for instance and you want to come back
in a new incarnation to fix that mistake
there is a story line but this story
line
is called evolution
growth.
Understand evolution not as linear but
progressive.
Progressive doesn't always mean linear.
Linearity equals cycles,
not progressive progression.
Progression is a growing
dynamics.
It's evolution.
Linearity, it's gravity. It's cycles.
There's something called a Fibonacci
sequence. You know what it is? It's when
you take numbers and you add them to
each other. You add to the last number,
it gives you a number that you add to
the last number, etc., etc., etc. That's
a Fibonacci sequence. Well, this
is the mechanism of evolution.
The sequence of number is not linear but
progressive.
Progressive equals the spiral of
evolution.
The Fibonacci sequence
the is the golden mean.
These numbers are progressive
and progressive can be evolving an
evolving line, spiral, sphere, cube,
complex geometrical structure or plasmic
concept. Even progressive evolves as a
fractal of itself
as does creation through evolution. So
you have
so to resume a little bit you have this
structure the latice of the universe
that's the skeleton of creation
and
this is where everything is structures
structured.
Now you need a dynamics
to give an impulse to this to create the
fractals.
It is the golden mean, the Fibonacci
sequence, the equation of progress,
evolution, the equation of evolution
from every point in that mesh in that
that grid
generates a fractal. A fractal that is
going to generate another fractal. And
this is growth.
Evolution. It's for matter. It works for
matter. It works for consciousness
also.
So
evolution
is
something that is always moving, always
dynamics and
it's a fractal. You know the Fibonacci
sequence is fractal
because not only it goes infinitely
in the addition of it on itself but also
in goes to infinity
at the beginning. It never is it never
starts.
We start the Fibonacci sequence with
zero and then one. But before zero, it
winds the other the other direction
to the infinitely small.
It's a constant flow.
So
linear equal linearity equals cycles.
Progressive equals the spiral of
evolution.
So if we go back in time to change the
past,
we change the present.
This is a fact. You are in this quantum
field.
If you everything is interconnected, you
have all your own interconnected dots.
Your story, your journey, your
experience is a mesh of dots. One dot
what quantum dots if you tingle it it's
going to influence another one that is
built from it. The present is built from
your actual present dot. Present is
moving all the time but
it's influenced by what just happened
and what this other past event
what it occurred in that that influenced
that made the present as it is today. So
if you tingle this little past dot, it
will um influence of course this one
will change. That's quantum entanglement
works with time as well. Okay.
So we go back in in the past, we change
the present not because of linearity of
time but because time is a quantum
field.
But is this action considered as an
update of the present? And where does
the old paradigm go?
I mean, you change something and the
present
changes. It's different now, but the old
present where it is.
Well, time also has its prime directive.
And you know the prime directive is
based on the universal law. I've said it
enough. The prime directive of the
Galactic Federation of Worlds as well as
the the Anarch Dakura are based on the
laws of the universe.
And it's exactly the same for time for
non-inference
not to disrupt the balance of the
creation.
This
the time field the quantum time field
has security security locks.
It's you cannot just change the past
like this. To change the present you
must physically
physically
interfere with the past. Why physically
and not just through consciousness
interface? because you need to have an
effect on the the the holographic matrix
of that point physical interface
to change this one.
It's it's a question of um atomic
vibration frequency. You need to modify
the frequency of vibration of certain um
elements of this
um matrix in the past to and by
entanglement change the present if you
want. It's it's easier to modify the
matrix in the present. I can tell you
you don't need to go back in time. You
have the power to change the reality
now. Do not try to change it from the
past. We have this power. The human have
this power to change the present the
matrix of reality.
I'm just checking the chat now to see
everything. Yes, you hear me well. So
time field has security locks
by only
being able to modify, alter
or interfere physically.
Only solid interference can affect time.
That is why people are sent back in time
to modify an event. They cannot do it by
consciousness connecting with the person
in the past. I'll develop that in in a
in a little moment shortly.
So to alter a timeline, you need um an
anchor point
in that timeline. Timeline I mean we you
understand what I mean. It's not a
timeline but it's better to understand
with these words. You need an anchor
point that will be the vector
to physically alter time. You need
technology because you need to travel
back in time physically. You need time
machines of some sort of or time
portals.
This is crucial for the understanding of
time.
In a medbed, for instance, when you want
to regress a body to a healthier state,
you're going to act physically on it on
the holographic on the holographic um
structure
of this this body. And you use
technology for that.
You can also use crystals, but that's a
little bit complex and it's still
technology anyway. So, you can interface
with your consciousness, your own
consciousness in another on another dot,
entangled dot, communicating with
yourself incarnated in the past or in
the future because you are of the same
frequency. It's you. But this will
remain as a communication in the higher
vibrational plane of your consciousness.
Maybe it will be experienced as a dream
for instance for example.
But to create an interaction
with actually an event in the past and
alter it.
You need to an anchor. I mean a physical
anchor.
You need to be there physically.
Time travel. Physical time travel.
What if I tune into the higher frequency
of my eternal consciousness? Because we
are eternal. The time field is eternal.
No beginning, no end. It's not linear
beginning and end.
It's vocabulary for linear thinking. So
I tune into the higher frequency or my
higher self and I tap into the time when
um
um I want to connect with my higher self
at the time when I was incarnating I
incarnated for instance um during the
French middle age let's say so I'm going
to tap into the time field to that dot
and I want to entangle
to that dot to interfere with interact
with it.
So I'm here and I see myself in the
French middle age for instance. Well, we
can have any type of conversation.
But if I say to her, hey on this day
someone is going to assassinate the
king.
The only thing that um will happen is
that my medieval self can feel a kind of
intuition or think that she dreamt
vaguely of the king being assassinated,
but she won't truly do anything about
it. Nothing will happen.
And that's in the best of conditions.
Most of the time
it doesn't interfere at all. You're
talking from a higher self to a higher
self.
What if now I travel to the past
physically with a time travel machine or
portal and I meet my medieval self and I
tell her, "Hey, on this day someone is
going to assassinate the king. So try to
prevent it."
Then
that is physical alteration
of the three-dimensional hologram of
reality,
time, space, consciousness.
On that day, my old self will save that
king and change the course of history.
Now what's going to happen?
What happens then to the old story when
that king is dead? Where has it gone?
Is it erased as if it never existed?
Is the old future be erased or it
continues to live somewhere?
Well,
it goes nowhere because it is stopped,
deconstructed.
When you modify something in the time
field, you don't create a split of
reality. You replace, you reattune. It's
all about vibrations and frequencies.
You rearrange
this little quantum dot
that's called me in the medieval times
in France. you rearrange it's the the
configuration
of your life and that's going to affect
other little dots that are connected to
this event the king dying etc but it
will replace things will be replaced
there is no split of reality because it
will be chaos
and that's not how the universe
functions
vap vaporized
many people believe that it creates It's
um a parallel timeline but it is a
misconception.
Why?
Because time is not linear.
Timelines is a perception not a thing.
If it were, it would create a parallel
timeline or parallel universe suddenly.
But your own universe,
what is that? It's all illusion. It's
not real.
It's not like a Y junction, you know.
It's not real. Things are staying
unique. They just change.
Evolution.
That's evolution.
Timelines
are an experience of reality
of a reality that is not linear.
Linearity as I said is experience when
consciousness entangles with gravity.
Time is a unified field. So what happens
then?
It generates what we call a local
paradigma.
The present is changed
and the old paradigm is deconstructed.
It just ends, ceased to exist.
The story when the king dies is
terminated.
The murderer will never sit on the
throne.
This changes is of course local as
altering only the events and beings
affected by this change.
It can have a huge collateral effect
such as changing the destiny of a
country or even a planet, a galaxy for
instance, or a tiny one such as when you
change your mind about killing a fly.
If someone travels to the past,
are you still following? Because it's a
lot of things. How is everybody doing?
I'm just looking at the chat.
Yes, the universe stands to perfection.
Kasmican just uh mentioned Jen Han.
Yes, you're still there. Okay, not
crying yet.
Okay, let's let's go ahead.
So um now
another time paradox story that is very
known. Um,
if someone travels to the past where and
when my mother meets my father.
Yes, I'm going there. And changes that
event, will I vaporize?
Answer.
The ancient story when you are born
ceases to exist.
Remember you modify this. This one
changes.
You cease to exist. Yes, you vaporize.
You cease to exist in the new present.
But it's not you vaporizing in in the
same present.
The law it's local paradigm. Everything
that will have been linked to you
existing will have changed also.
Sometimes it can go very far. So you're
not here anymore. There's a new present
with you not here. the same present but
the local there's a local paradigm that
will have been diff different a
different local paradigm
you cease to exist in the new present
considering that the present doesn't
exist
as such as you knew it time is a flow
a current in the field
not linear the connection between That
alteration of an event in the past and
the current moment is not a linear
connection but a quantum entanglement.
So you
if you suddenly are not born, you're not
here. Your consciousness is somewhere
else but the body this life is not here
anymore. Okay?
That's when there's been a physical
interaction that breaks infringes the
universal laws. Okay?
Because the universe doesn't like this.
Creator doesn't like this. It's not
natural. Okay? That's experiment
between technologized beings who want to
play with that.
So time
as as an infinite field is composed of
flowing data
and electrical neur neuronal
connections.
The flow of time is not linear but all
pervading. It's all alive and conscious.
Imagine a big brain,
big mind. It's a mind. It's alive and
conscious. That's time
and also space and also consciousness.
Um, now
there's a question
um I've been asked a lot.
Going to have a bit of water. Tea
actually.
So question that many of you are asking
when
no I am my last incarnation was on
planet era in the pleades. I chose to
undergo the the the program not as dying
and incarnating but as leaving my body
in stasis to come to earth. Why did I do
that? Because era is not my planetary
biometrics.
I have
chosen to live on era as a choice to
experience something but I'm not from
era. So I'm not part of the the De'Ra
biometrics. Okay, my biometrics it's a
Maria in the Alia star system in the
Alderon galaxy 45 million years from
here. So it was easier for me to just go
on a pod
and um so when I come back to error
I will reintegrate my body in stasis.
Okay, that's for a fact.
I'm talking about me, but that's the
case of millions of star seeds. So,
because we have changed the timeline of
this galaxy now, it's done,
which is on the gravity linear time.
Okay, the galaxy and the dark future has
ceased to exist.
There is a different future now that is
already there.
300 years later on era
the envoy program
never existed.
So we could say
because there was no need for it because
the dark timeline never existed.
So I could say I do not have a body in
stasis.
What will happen? Is that a time
paradox?
Well, do you think that the people who
created the envoy programs didn't think
about that?
Everyone comes home safely, but home
will be a different place. Let me
explain this to you.
The body in stasis
as the buildings where they are they are
secured in a time distortion hull.
This means that you will safely
reintegrate your stasis body.
But in a world that has changed. The
whole building is a time traveling
machine. The whole pod even sometimes
depends where your pod is. The pods are
time traveling machines. They are in a
distortion hull. You will be a time
traveler who has landed in a new
environment with different parameters.
You know after all it is only the
equivalent of 300 years
which is not even a generation for the
people on era.
The parents
of the time traveler are still alive.
We are on era time. 300 years on era
time
in some places where the change has
hasn't affected that much.
Everything will seem normal
to some of the envoys returning home.
It will be like waking up from from a
dream and they will find their family
waiting for them.
While some envoys will return to a world
where the impact is greater and then
they may not find a people they they
know or they may find people who didn't
even die in a war that never existed.
That's the good part.
This was the contract. You all were
aware of these conditions before you
accepted.
You knew the risks not to see your
family again.
And what about the rest of the
Federation troops who didn't participate
in the envoy program? Those who have
physically traveled back in time to
alter its course,
responding the call of the the Zen
Zenate.
Well, these ones they remain physically
in the new version of time 300 years
earlier than when they left
because they are still in the past
now and here. Thoran is still in his
past here
as I am.
They jumped out of the old version of
time to become time travelers.
Okay, they got here v via time traveling
technology.
So we can consider they traveled in a
time distortion technology when they go
back now 300 years earth years. No not
earth years sorry 300 years era years
era years into the future. They will be
like the envoys
time travelers returning home after
escaping the time paradox. You know
the curators of the envoy programs will
have made sure that all the data is
secure
that those remained on the home world
know who we are and what we have done.
It's only 300 years
in era time,
you know, give or take 20 years of
earth time scale
in comparison in
correspondence.
It's very exciting to go back and
discover what our worlds have become.
and many of them have already gone back
home. So now there's a thing
300 years on era is equivalent to 20
years on earth.
So one year
one earth year
is the equivalent of 15 era years.
Take into account the orbital speed of
era around Ashara its star TEA combined
with the fact that the entire galaxy is
on the fifth density orbital time as a
standard followed by the galactic
alliance and that is important fifth
density
time
that's the
the the the balance time of the galaxy
Nataru is on fifth density in average
And they're above and below. But the
fifth density is the the the the matrix
the most important is a prominent
density of the galaxy. That's where
everything is happening.
So
there is another universal law. The
higher the density is, the faster time
is experienced.
Because when the particles of matter
vibrate at a faster rate or at a higher
frequency if you want to call it like
this
time is experienced
faster. Time is not faster. Time is
time. It's a quantum field. But it it's
the experience that we have of it
regarding to regarding our density that
seems as that is perceived as faster or
slower because the the particles of our
bodies are vibrating faster or slower.
Have you noticed this already? Yes.
Time seems to flow faster than when you
were a kid, right?
Well, it's because Earth is shifting
progressively into a faster density of
matter.
Have you ever wondered why happy moments
seem to flow faster than sad moments?
Of course, happiness is a higher
frequency than sadness.
So, it is experienced
faster when we are in the frequency of
happiness.
But all this it's only the way time is
experienced. It is not what absolute
time is really. To experience the time
field as you say as I said you need to
uh step out of gravity
out of material linearity.
So um
earth is on the third density time.
It rotates slower transiting. Okay, it
rotates slower than error
and that is on in on the fifth density
time. Okay, faster time.
Universal time is the same. It is just
experienced differently.
Make sense? Well, it's not over.
Something else coming. Here's something
else.
What if we
what if we would talk about
the dark fleet paradigm?
Oh, what is that?
Remember 300 years they they came the
federation came from 300 years in the
future to here. But 300 years on the
galactic time scale,
fifth density on earth is
20 years.
Okay. In the third density,
it's slower time.
Yeah.
300 years. When the Andromedan Council
asked the Galactic Alliance to send
troops back in time, it was 300 years on
the galactic time.
Everywhere, everyone is
uh counting on this galactic orbital
time, fifth density.
That's the norm. So, the dark fleet were
a galactic threat already 20 years ago.
So
in earth time frame 20 years make more
sense because earth is in the third
density.
It makes 30 years for the fifth density
people. If we don't need to we must not
try to fit this on the linear time.
Okay. Okay.
While 300 years pass, you understand in
the galactic time few density 20 years
pass on earth. The change in the
parameters of the ancient timeline where
the dark fleet would have taken over the
galaxy
was achieved and stabilized recently in
early 2022 in Earthtime reference
only months before the time portal
window would close. I'm going to talk
about that.
So
I really want to insist in that. Forgive
me for those who get it, who got it for
the first time. But it needs to be
really clear because that is the key to
understand everything else that's
coming, especially the secret space
programs
on the galactic time scale, 300 years in
the future. On the galactic time scale,
the Andromedan say, "Hey, 300 years in
the past,
the dark fleet was about to sign an
agreement something and we need to stop
that. So go back 300 years in the past."
But when that happened,
it was 20 years in the past if we take
in account Earth time, third density
time. So that's important.
experience 300 for them. Experience two
20 here.
So
the the stabilization of the ancient
uh the new timeline I mean I don't like
to say timeline but the new parading was
achieved and stabilized recently in 2022
December earth time only month before
the time portal window would close
we had to go back to the source to earth
at the moment moment when the dark fleet
would sign a great power sharing
alliance with the Nebu Empire and rule
Nataru despicably.
It would have been game over for
everyone.
Thanks to the Zenate,
the exact time paradigm key was located.
It was a time window on Earth that was
very narrow. a gap of five years
from December 21st, 2027
to December 21st, 2022.
The 21st of December are solstice dates
for Earth. It's a gravitational
geoposition that allows time portals to
be open or closed.
The mission was to destroy the Nebu at
the same time, kick the dark fleet
mother faction of the star system and
the galactic alliance.
You know, they didn't have the the
resource to fight a global war against
the dark fleet and the allied neu allies
Nebu and their allies seek everyone at
the same time. Elements of the equation
had to be taken down
to weaken the equation.
So to prevent this dramatic alliance
between the dark fleet and the nebu to
happen, it was easier to neutralize the
nebu ruse. You can't fight the whole
army composed of sikar nebu dark fleet
to ally together because that's what
they were about to do. Well, dark and
sikar was already together, but they had
they were about to merge with the nebu
which was big thing. So you you take
down one.
The easiest was the Nebu because they
had a weak point, their queen. They took
the queen thanks to Netor. And now, you
know, it was easier to attack them. Then
they removed the dark fleet from the
star system. Then they could not sign
any more disagreement there because at
the same time the Nebu were uh
destroyed.
You're never cautious enough. So that
was it.
These were the worst years
in this ruth ruthless temporal war.
The job was done before the December
21st, 2022 time portal closed.
And the temporal war was won.
Everybody's there.
So
20 years in the third density
is why the secret space programs are
based on a 20 years maximum schedule
because after December 2022
the timeline changes
and they cannot go beyond that it
changes. They cannot go beyond that
further in time because it disappeared.
It's disconstructed. It stops. It's
non-existent.
It has merged into the new future, the
new timeline
and there's no point of no return.
There's no point of return. I mean, this
is why all the dark secret space
programs associated with the dark fleet
and their acolytes in the dark military
programs that we call the 20 and back
that were created 20 or more years ago
all ended before 2022
because the timeline changed and
stabilized at that exact moment.
There was no way back from that point.
It had become a temporal dead end.
So what happened to the people who did
more than 120 and back program? Well,
those who began service early were able
to do successive shifts
before 2022.
Others who began later served under the
same limitation of the December 2022
time collapse.
For these it resulted in multiple
versions of themselves or altars
which they sometimes mistakenly uh
identified as clones.
Although they were real cloning programs
but you know you understand they they
did several those who did several 20 and
back programs.
It was done before 2022. That was the
the the wall.
So they they were it's like the quantum
field.
You are meeting someone. Okay. So I
bought these things for something.
I'm going to use them.
I went to the trouble to buy this and
and buy marker pens. So
okay. So I don't know
I want to check the chats everybody.
Yeah. Okay. So
um you are here.
Can you see this? Yes. Can you see this
little point? Okay. Okay. That's the the
moment where a child is abducted into
for instance the 20 and back where you
sign up for the 20 and back. You're
going to do your 20 years.
Okay. Oh, we don't see anything. Going
to do your 20 years and then it's over.
20.
You are sent back in time.
regressed. Time regressed. Okay. But
then that's the wall.
But then
you are signing up for another 20 years.
So you're going to do another one. I'm
going to say you're here.
You're going to do another one.
20 years up. Go back.
While you're here, you are also here
and you see yourself and you say, "Oh my
god, that's me. That's be a clone of
me." No, it's your altar. It's still
you. Okay? This is you and this is you
as a whole. This is time travel. This is
time travel. Physical time travel. Okay?
And
you can interact.
There's no parading.
You can absolutely interact. That's why
they want people to that's that's the
law. They want people to forget also
because
if you don't forget like Tony Rodrig you
change the present
because there's been physical
interaction and you remember
everything's going to happen and you
know so the the you that's here for
instance is doing that for a second
time. You are doing that the second
time. Okay.
So
you're meeting yourself as an an
individual separately physically and you
tell you tell yourself you tell yourself
you said hey at that point in time here
there's a big reptilian that is going to
eat your arm and so avoid it. So the
little guy here, he avoids it, but he
change stuff that maybe
were disastrous for the dark fleet or
for the enemy because he kills the
reptilian and he managed to escape or he
does something very naughty.
But you that that's why when you come
back here when you come back here your
memory is wiped that when you sign up a
second time you don't know and you're
going to meet this reptilian and be
eaten
or not or something else but anyway
you know
you can meet that's it that's not a
clone that's you as a time traveler and
there can be
many other you many many many many and
you think there's an army of clothes but
maybe people do one 20 and back two 20
and back three 20 and back after three
it's difficult because
uh it's not working very well for the
the the mind the consciousness they
don't do a lot they do one two
three is very rare
so I knew I need to use this thing
um you
You meet your altars.
You are the sum of all that you have
been all along.
And it was always you as a whole in your
incarnations.
And to say I am not I was or I will be
is the right thing. It is in tempmporal.
Our consciousness is eternal. Um
it's not when you extract yourself okay
when you are on the linear time
um
you think I am I was I will be I was I
am I will be when you are out of linear
time in the the the the
quantum time field you think I am I am I
am I am I am I am I am I am
I am is in temporal
even when you are on the linear time I
am
when the time you say I am you've you
already moved in the future and the
future is now the present
I am since you've started watching this
video
you're not at the same place in the
galaxy as you were an hour ago
you know the present is constantly
moving
The I am is eternal. It's moving. It's a
it's a dynamic, the flow of the the the
time field, you know.
So yes, it's extraordinary that you can
converse with past existences of yours.
Have you ever connected with yourself in
the future? You can in a future
incarnation with consciousness, with the
higher self. It's perfectly possible.
You know, time exists as a unified
field. So you can do connect to any
point of it. It's all entangled.
You can talk to yourself in the past.
You can surely talk to yourself in the
future.
Wherever you stand
in the time field,
wherever you stand in a time field, you
are an equidistance
of everything.
like in space,
like in consciousness.
So, let's go over some points to make
sure we get this.
When you talk to aspects of yourself,
is this modifying events in the past?
No. You will need physical interaction
for that. You need to actually transpose
physically in a moment in spaceime.
When I speak to myself as incarnated in
other temporal moments, I am speaking to
my own consciousness. Call it the higher
self.
Unless I travel physically through time
to connect to a particular moment, it
does not create any incidence.
If for example, I am telling my higher
self who lived in Atlantis, hey, get on
that spacecraft before the big wave
hits.
that will not have any incidence but if
I actually travel back in time
physically to that moment well yes I can
meet physically with myself back and
influencer
that's why physical time travels is
unethical unnatural and requires
technology because it's unnatural it
goes against universal laws of evolution
the creator's prime directive
because time is a field and not a linear
construct.
Can you naturally choose to incarnate
from the future? Well, no. As this would
be a deroggation as the envoy programs
were with the creation of time dilation
pods.
Incarnating in a planetary matrix starts
a cycle and you can only go forward
because it serves evolution progression.
Progress
and a spir spiral of evolution is
progressive.
The golden mean the Fibonacci sequence
cannot go backwards. The numbers can
only add to themselves. Construct this
is evolution. The meaning of creation.
There is no past, no future. There is
only the quantum field, the quantum time
field.
Where in the absolute you are not
subject to linear gravity.
Extract yourself
from linear thinking.
Think as the field.
So would you like to talk about time
machines?
Uhhuh.
The time machines.
Well, thanks to Dan Willis.
Um
Dan Willis told me yesterday about the
Delawir quantum holographic camera
project, an interdimensional imaging
device.
Um, so I'm going to share.
Um, where am I? Share.
Okay. Okay.
It's on this website. Um,
screen.
Select Marcel Vogel Crystal Research.
Yes. Okay.
So um you can see here I hope it's uh
working. You see
above marcelvog.org/came.html.
So this camera
was um something that was able to
regress the vision the hologram of for
instance a body and take photos of it in
the past that um hologram of a woman
that was the body of a woman that was
regressed to the fetus state and the
photo was taken. So, you have all the
blueprints if you go to that address and
the photos of what it looks like
and all the experiments. Um,
so I have a few slides I want to show
you.
H Okay.
Um so
it's an interdimensional imaging device
and u there's a key statement in the
opinion of de laawir who said time is a
vector of magnetic
spectrum and that spectrum has a place
in itself for events. There is a
preysical world in which the camera
might be expected to operate.
So, um, where are my slides? Here.
Okay.
Um,
difficult.
The slides are not working, so I'm not
going to lose time. Uh, you we have the
address. So, um, I'll put the the
address is
marcelvog.org/camera.html
marcelvogal.org/camera.html.
I had written that on a slide. Uh uh uh.
Okay.
Second attempt.
Okay. Not working.
So um this is a very interesting uh time
time machine that was affecting the the
hologram of of a body for instance of
reality. And this is a technology that
is used in the medical beds. you are
able to attune the holog the damage
hologram to um an earlier version
that was healthier and as Jinhan says
the universe tends towards perfection.
So the the dissonant material will
attune to the resonant material
naturally and it will heal.
Talking about time machines now more
specifically
we have there's the chronovvisor. So
that's a chronovvisor. Uh that dawir
machine is also a chronovvisor.
Um
another chronovvisor is the looking
glass looking glass device that was
given by the neighbor. It was a cube
given by the neighbor. There was one in
area 51. There was I think two
uh maybe three I think at my to my
knowledge about two. Um and they
they allowed people to especially
politicians to uh
to alter time to modify time.
And
when I'm going to tell you about the the
Dan Anunnaki technology time device,
you're going to see that there's a great
parallel with the Nebu
looking glass cube
a lot. It's two different technologies,
but it's working for the same purpose.
changing events
to see changing events in the present to
see how it's going to go in the future.
And if it doesn't go as you want, you
rechange the present. You do something
else. Politicians have been doing that a
lot with this device.
Another chronisor. A pity I don't have
the slides. Um I have them. I have it in
here.
is the device I met on the metron ship.
Um,
here we go. Here it is.
Or was it in the cedars? Oh, it's in the
cedars. Excuse me. So many books. Um,
okay. Yes, my little thing. Wrong book.
Distract myself. So I don't expect you
you find it. Um this is
a chronovvisor on the metron ship.
There was a tube with a sort of plasma
in it and you would put your hands
interface with it and you would
interface your consciousness a bit with
like with a crystal. Yeah.
And this would show you, you say a date
in time and it will show you um
the future, but it's a chronovvisor.
It's not like the looking glass
uh that the nebu gave to the earthling
which were chronovisor as well, but it
was more looking how things are going to
change. No, this one is tells you
exactly how it's going to happen.
So that's something that is very very
important because this device this alpha
centurion uh chronovvisor
tells you the real future
how it's going to be after all the
temporal wars. It's actually projecting
in the future and tells you how it is
stable. That's how I could see 2000
years in the future. And there's been uh
pictures I publish in this book drawings
of the future as I as I saw it, you
know.
So, um it's all in there.
Um
and also there's uh so now something I
haven't uh spoken about um really yet.
Um it's the the device the anunaki
device the amala
amala
the arala is the registry of future
events.
It's a holographic device
that can read time.
It has a holographic screens and you
interfere in the same way as with any
other regular advanced technology
devices.
through consciousness.
The amala is used as a sort of cosmic
calendar
displaying important events that will
occur on a given planet in the future
based on the algorithm of current
events. It is not an absolute prediction
of the future but rather a projected
calculation of how things are more
likely to unfold based on the algorithm
of the current data.
So the results change
as the present events unfold.
It is more of a tool than say
chronovvisor for instance like the one I
accessed twice on the met ship. What I
saw on the metron ship was a fixed
immovable feature. The amala is not. The
amala is a time calculating device. You
can consult this device whenever you
want to make an important decision and
see what the future consequences would
be. You can see as far as you want, but
it becomes a bit blurry as you look
further in time.
The reason why the Amala is not
perfectly reliable technology is that
its calculation do not take in account
possible external inputs creating future
disturbances that are not listed in the
current algorithm of the present.
A chronovvisor like the one on the metal
chip for instance in the contrary will
see the future as a whole with all the
inputs on the way into the equation.
So there is one amala amala
that is located on the Nibberu ship of
course um a large room with a high
ceiling and um there's uh all sorts of
equipment around and um and there's this
oval metal mirror.
It's about 9 ft high. It's mounted on a
pedestal and you put you so you put on a
a large headset that looks like a
futuristic helmet with diodes and um and
kind of weird stuff sticking out. And
there's it's carved with very fine fine
symbols as well, finally edged symbols.
And you place your hands on the two
triangular pads of a console in front of
the mirror.
And then they lit up when your
consciousness
interfaces. And at the same time, the
diodes on the helmet, they they um they
kind of whistle.
And anac technology works pretty much
the same way for most things, you know,
interface of consciousness.
So you stand there with your helmet and
your your hands on that these um
triangles and you face the mirror. Okay.
And so remember it's not a real future
telling machine. It's a calculation
device, you know. So you need to ask for
a date. No, sorry. You need not to ask
for a date
like on a metal mothership, but you need
to ask for the result of an action.
So
for instance you say okay
100 years if
I do this what will be the consequence
in 100 years okay and you see you see it
you see it
so there's a lot of people a lot of
anarch people who have used this this
machine so here on board the nibir who
just locked it in the room and with DNA
frequency only him can access it can
open the door because that was starting
to be a game with uh you know this um
dysfunctional family and le and all the
rest. So, and it looks a little bit like
the looking glass device that was kept
um in Nevada.
You just look at the what are going to
be the consequences of your actions, you
know.
So, um
yeah.
So, this is what I could say about um
time traveling machines, time looking
machine um and time
So
it see it sounds complex when you are
in on linear time but um you know
it isn't
it isn't in the time quantum build.
So, I hope here we go. I hope you enjoy
this. Um I try to repeat points over and
over again to make sure everyone
understands it because it's explic
expressing a concept a reality that is
in nonlinear time with linear time
expressions
to people who live on linear time and
think on linear time. So it's was a bit
of a challenge
but I hope you uh you enjoyed it. Um, I
am now going to answer the Q&A.
So, um,
and we're going to have some fun.
There we go.
Where my looking glass devices? Present
looking glass device.
That's my looking glass device for the
present.
It is
reading glasses. Okay.
Okay.
Now I'm accessing the Q&A uh section. So
I won't be able to see the chat anymore.
So if there is um sound problem or
something like that uh
I'm going to check the private uh chat.
Okay.
I hope everything will go well. Okay.
Let's let's go for these questions.
Okay. So what do we got there that we
have there?
Okay.
Oh, before you go, I need to say some
not going to go now. There's a
questions, but um I will repeat this
after the Q&A, but um I will be in
Denver, Colorado this September 27th 29.
Well, not in Denver actually in
Westminster. It's between Denver and
Boulder, but it's Denver airport. That's
why we say Denver for the galactic
spiritual informers connection
conference the third one and that's
going to be amazing. Um I'm going to
talk about consciousness but
consciousness tech interface
technologies.
So that's going to be again and
disclosed things that will be disclosed
later on publicly but the first time
will be at JC. There will be a lot of
first times for this JC. You know that
JP is going to be on stage.
Yes. And who's who's else is going to be
on stage is the brilliant sim David
there. He just accept to be on stage. He
won't actually he requests said no I'm
not coming on Zoom. I'm coming on stage.
I'm climbing on that stage. I I'm sick.
I don't care. I'm climbing on that
stage. He'll be fine. He'll be safe and
uh going to have so much fun.
Oh my goodness. Michael Salah, Christian
Northrup, Dr. Christian Northrup, sorry,
Dr. Lee Merritt, Alex Kolia will be in
not on stage but in the public with you
guys and girls, Dr. Michael Salah, Josh
Moya, Melanie, and
Tony Rodrig, the handsome Tony Rodrig.
I'm sure I forget people, but uh there's
going to be a lot of people on that
stage. And Denny Henderson as well. So,
um,
if you can make it, that'd be amazing.
Be amazing.
First question, 44 votes.
Hi, Helena. You are awesome. Thank you
very much. What happens to your era,
body, consciousness, and future timeline
after you have come back in time to help
planet Earth ascend? Oh, I've answered
this one. I'm I'm reading it. Reading
it. After your current timeline,
lifetime, sorry.
Does your consciousness go back to your
body in stasis on error? Oh yes, I
answered this question. Um, will you
remember what happened? Yes, of course.
Because I arrived in my time dilation
bubble and uh I'll remember everything
because it's doesn't go through
incarnation.
Yes, because I go through a pod. So I'm
not going through incarnation and
forgetting stuff. No.
So uh thank you Moira. Um there was a
question I
in it I had an answer.
See you in September. Next question. 32
votes from Mark Verver.
Dear Elena, we all know that our history
and time has been altered.
We don't even know for sure we live in
the year 2024.
Terra time. That is right.
Please share with us where our timeline
was altered and why. I know that the
aids and the federation are able to
share the truth about our time. Thank
you so much for your information, your
love and compassion for Terra. I love
you. I love you too. I love all of you.
So, um, as I said, it was altered uh the
month during the month before because
you don't alter timeline like this. It
takes 5 years, a little bit less. So, it
was completed in December 2022.
Um,
a little bit before actually, but it was
a process, you know. Um,
so
and I have answered to the the rest in
the the the webinar. So, you you got
already your answers, Mark.
There's a There's a lot of questions
I've answered already too already. So
with 30 votes, Edwin Ketah, hello Edwin,
how are you? Dear Elena, thanks for all
the information you have given us. You
have mentioned that the deep state is
collapsing. Yes, it is because it is so
secret. I don't actually know what is
happening to the deep state. Do you the
federation of some other entity have a
way of monitoring the fall of the deep
state?
Can you give us a percentage remaining
like you did when the regressives were
being kicked out of our solar system?
I do not have this technology to know
what's going on with the deep state. It
is secret because it's an operation that
is ongoing.
Okay. When it's ongoing, we're not given
the details of the operation because it
will compromise the operation. Um, all I
can say it is really collapsing. are
still people in power.
Uh they still have power. But um if you
follow my Star Nation news in the Star
Nation news 35
two weeks ago, Thoran Erdon gave uh
information about the disclosure plan
and uh he said that because you cannot
take them by front, it would cause chaos
and damages, you know, collateral
damages. So they use ruse and
infiltrated a lot of these um
different organizations of the deep
state. It was a long process of
infiltration to collapse them by the
inside. They they did exactly like the
enemy does you know they collapse the
the organization from the inside.
That's as simple as that. So
I cannot tell more just that it's
collapsing and losing power. It it it's
it plays like if it doesn't, but it
does. It does. It does. It does.
A question by Arthur Worth.
33 votes. Elena. Did Prince Ia soul
separated some 450 year th,000 years ago
from the nine then dropped down into
five density to incarnate into is No, it
didn't drop from from the nine. It's not
it's nothing to do with the nine.
Um,
hence explaining why Thorhan stated that
he is the third most powerful person in
the universe, explaining his
extraordinary abilities to create life
as a cosmic alchemist and other skills.
Thank you.
um
is the third most powerful being in this
universe after the nine you know uh
because he's a cosmic alchemist he
underwent through incredible
transformation the abra transformation
the immortality of the body also is
quite painful and challenging you know
uh so um
the result is amazing.
Postcrytom, I see Julian Assange is a
very important person in the great
awakening movement. I received an email
from his brother. Oh, Gabriel Shipton
thanking me for helping them free
Julian. We are celebrating in Australia
his victory. Arthur, were you part of
his liberation? You've got to tell us
more about that now, Arthur.
We want to know more. We want to know
more. Um, so, um, I see comments
underneath. Oh. Oh. Oh,
no. You didn't say anything. Okay. Well,
you know, just before
uh the day before we learned about
Julian Assange, be liberated.
Thoran said in an SNN it was number 36
last week last Monday. He said something
very very very important. He said no it
was in 35th. Oh yes. He said
it is not this the great reveal that
will set you free but your endeavors to
set yourselves free that will allow the
great reveal that will bring the great
reveal.
And the following morning, Julian Asen
was liberated. So I think he's
he was mentioning this as well. I'm
sure.
So uh is time really speeding up? A
question from Yenna Spiro. Um
yes, because we are moving into the
fifth density. So
the the galaxy is the time of the galaxy
is faster than on earth third density.
So we are we have entered in this fifth
density zone area in the galaxy. We've
left our third density
black mesh whole thing and we've moved
into this density, this fifth density.
And now the the star system is really
calibrating and it comes always from the
stars. So have you noticed how the the
star the sun has changed from yellow to
white recent in the recent years
decades.
Um
when we were a kid we were drawing the
sun and yellow you know coloring in
yellow. Now it's white. It's really
white. Slightly yellow golden but white.
We are moving into the fifth density and
so the time is experienced experienced
faster as I explained earlier on
with 31 vote car
how are you
um hena if Thoran and yourself is from
dark future 300 years old um from now
does it create a time paradox when he
returns to the future I've oh I've I've
answered this one. I've answered this
one, Carl. So, you've got your answer uh
earlier on. Um question 29 from AA
Louise Carter. Hello, Aina. Hi, you have
mentioned the importance of the prime
directive, but why were why sorry, why
were so many ET colonies like the Ail or
Celuzi allowed to settle here and
interbread with us? Doesn't this go
against the law of non-inference? So
it was done regarding the prime
directive when the the the ail and the
celuzi came here it was in the program
of collaboration of the earth alliance
to collaborate on technologies. So it
was all
inside of a frame, you know, inside of
um um a program, an operation. And so it
was not a bridge of the prime directive
because it was in an operation to save a
world. So that's that's the the
difference.
247 votes
and you are enlightenment bell. How are
you?
How are you?
So your question is, dear Elena, as it
is said, time is not linear. Past,
present, and future all exist at the
same time. Is it possible for each of us
as a fractal of source to go back
through consciousness to a past time
point of a linear timeline to change a
regretful decision made at that time
point? How will it affect our present
life? much love and gratitude. You can
do it by physical time travel. You can
do it.
You can interface your consciousness
with your own personal consciousness at
that moment in time in the quantum time
field.
But that will not really affect your
actions.
You need to really physically go back at
that point and change the past. What
happens as I explained the timeline just
stops existing the story line I'd say.
So here we go.
Andrew Maisy 29 votes.
Anax
says time is a bubble where all moments
are equidistant from eternity. How
beautiful description of the quantum
time field. So there are many nows and
or everything is happening at once. Yes.
But if so, what is the reference point
for a particular now to be able to
travel there? Please elaborate.
Um
what is the reference point for a
particular now to be able to Okay.
evolution progress
the Fibonacci sequence of evolution
there are story lines the story line of
your journey that is a progressive
evolution
a progressive
golden mean
and
um that's how I could um
describe all the points or the numbers
being linked to each other on this line
of the Fibonacci sequence the golden
mean you have all the points and it's
not a timeline it's a story line I
cannot describe it better than this
though
question 28
Um from
hello Christine Louie.
Oh it's a long one. Elena I practice
energy healing and my question is when I
use myself as a channel for divine
energy to go to the person on the
quantum or distant healing. Can I go
back in time? For example, a few days
before the person got an infection so I
can perform the healing on the cut to
prevent the present infection.
Yes, that's how the medical beds work.
Um,
you
tune into the hologram of the person. If
it's not by technology, it's by your
consciousness as you did. And
you are going to regress, rewind,
rewind the hologram until the moment it
was not infected. For instance, a wound
was not infected. And you just imprint
it and anchor it in the body. You take
this vision, this holographic vision,
and you imprint it in the body. You
superimpose it to the sick body and the
universe tends to perfection as we know
it. The the the infection will that is
dissolent will be dis dissolved and sees
will merge into resonance so will heal
when you superimpose the resonant
version of the body on it.
So that's what's going to it's going to
happen.
So um
obviously you did it and it worked. Uh
what I can read. So well done. See,
thank you Elena and Princia in advance
to if you can say something. I think
we're going to be good.
Thank you Christine.
So yes, you can do it and you you've
done it. It worked. So that's the way to
go.
Question from Jane Hernandez.
Hello Elena. Which ET race create the
time construct here on Terra? Will the
perception of time change when Terra
sense? Thank you for all you do to
educate and keep us informed.
There's no iterates time. Time has never
been created and will never seize. It's
the field
and no one created it. It's it was there
to be there. That's very difficult to
encompass this notion of never born,
never die, but that's how it is.
And yes, the perception of time of
course accelerates as we go higher
densities.
This matter vibrates faster.
Question from Moj Kendrick. Dear Elena,
do you think we exist as previous
incarnations of ourselves or does each
incarnation end like a book that cannot
be changed?
So yes, we exist as previous
incarnations of ourselves in the quantum
time field simultaneously.
And
you can change the book, rewrite the
book if you have a physical pen.
You go physically in the past to rewrite
the book.
And that goes against the ethic of the
universal laws, but it's can be done
with technology.
Question from Josephine.
Do many star seeds or voice come from
the future like you and Toran? And by
what process can a soul incarnate in the
past?
Oh, I've answered these questions,
Josephine. So, um I'm going to pass the
other ones. Lucky I've answered them
already. We're going to go fast.
Um,
Mo,
hey
Mo. Oh, I'm so glad. Oh, I miss you so
much. You know, Moenu, your the curator
of the the conference in Tokyo, which
was absolutely amazing. I was treated
like um an empress. Um,
Japanese people are so beautiful.
Anyway, dear beautiful Elena, I would
like to know if we can time travel. Then
what happens when we physically meet
ourselves in the future or in the past?
Can we give some advice to ourselves for
the decision uh that we are making at
that time and change the outcome? Thank
you for all your love and all you do for
the humanity. Love from Japan Myoko. Oh,
I love you so much. Um
we can ch we can travel in time
physically. We can also and change the
outcome. We can also interface our
consciousness to the consciousness of
ourselves
in a previous life and try to
influence influence. It's very difficult
very very very difficult to access to go
through all the layers of consciousness
throughout the the thinking mind of the
person. It's possible
uh but there it's so difficult because
the universe has you know time has its
own safety locks
um you know sometimes you can dream of
yourself in the future you know um Danny
Henderson um tells this story and it's I
think it's in her book u angels in moons
and aliens or if it's not it will be
surely in the the next one when her
future self materializes as a hologram
I'm transplant at the in front of her
bed and uh she's beautiful. She's a
plleadian and she's she's and she's
there and she's telling her guidance and
um she's telling her things um advice.
So you can you can do this if you're
really skilled. You can project
yourself, but it's very hard. The best
way to in to
surely and safely and easily modify the
past is to go there physically with
technology.
Thank you, Mo. Have a nice day.
23. Radu
leganu,
you won a book on my telegram. Radu,
yes. Uh, on I have a telegram official
chat where I do um quiz where I send
signed copies of my book. So, uh, I have
a stock of book here and I need to find
homes. to uh register to my telegram
channel official and you can win um
books signed copies. So anyways, Radu,
what happens if you die during the 20
and back programs? Oh, good question.
Does your soul return to the original
point where you were taken out of your
body? Tony Rodrig's soul return after
committing suicide, but that was a
different technology. Thank you.
No matter the technology, no matter the
the species and where you are when you
that's that's a way of ending the
program. But um you suffer tremendously
you know um suicide the condition when
it happens it's
it
strain your soul. It's really the the
the the travel back is is strainous.
It's it's difficult you know but you
eventually go back to the the point when
you were taken when you started the the
journey. So um
I am sure of this and it worked for Tony
you know. So
thank you Ru.
Um, next question with 22 votes from
Marijana
Marijuana.
Alex Kolier had a recent guest Rob
Potter.
Okay.
Who stated that he received a message
from the Queen of Venus.
What are your thoughts about it? Thank
you for all you do.
Okay.
There is no queen on Venus.
There is no queen on Venus. It's um
planet with federate. It's a federated
cities system. You have
underground cities that are of
Talenturans
um different races and they all
federated
under the the leadership not the
leadership the I don't like this word
and it's not the case under the
management of and the administration of
the council of al-Nam
the Galactic Federation of Worlds
is there as sorry as well.
There are also all members of the
Galactic Federation of Worlds,
but there is no royalty. There is no
queen.
There's no queen on Venus.
I've been there twice and I know this.
Um, you know, in my work, I
I go to meetings sometimes and I meet
with diplomats and I meet with sometimes
Valthor.
I'm It's not my personal contact. Valor,
it's just someone I meet in my work
sometimes, but that's all. And he's very
distant.
Valor doesn't communicate with
civilians.
Uh, he's an ambassador.
It's the difference with an emissary is
an ambassador. An ambassador works at
government levels with official
government officials is not is no time
for the public.
Um that's his work. Okay. because of the
classified of his work and secrecy of
his work.
There's a lot of people pretending to
talk to him or
being him, opening um YouTube channels
or even pretending being him. I've
covered this already, but regarding the
queen of Venus, there's no queen on
Venus and everything going around this
Queen of Venus thing, all the the the
the
Earth ladies with red barretts and a lot
of makeup and and and they're not
Venuians. The whole thing is a scam and
it's someone's story. I've been in
contact with this this person and his
hacky and um I have to say I've seen for
myself. I've listened to them
and I felt the frequency. I've listened
to them and um I told them
um it doesn't work with me. I have other
information. It's not what I I was shown
physically. It's not the place where
I've been. It's sorry. So we're friends
but that's it. So, you know, there's no
point. There was never a point to say
anything. But, um, if you ask the
question, there's no queen on Venus.
Um, and whatever these people are
spreading as
stupid things about me and
a weekend or whatever. Um,
it's because they want to protect a
business. That's all. So, um, that's my
answer. It's very harsh. But um
my job is not an easy job. I'm not doing
this job to be popular. I'm doing this
job to
and to make friends. I'm doing this job
to
for the mission and to tell the truth.
So that's my knowledge.
There's no queen.
So
next question.
Okay. Um,
do the andromedans descend from the
tile? Oh, David. Um,
they were at the origin
a tal human race, but that they've
migrated so much so much so much. They
they arrived on Titawin in the
uh Andromeda constellation the star
system Titawin and after a long period
of migrating and transforming
interbreeding with species and they're
now the beautiful tall blue humans they
are they are absolutely magnificent um
I've met some and some zenate on board
the excelsure I haven't spoken to them
and I could see I I mean, wow. They are
really thin and and elegant and they
walk like this with grace and you know
slow and they're really really
beautiful. So, but I've never interacted
with one. Yeah, they're really really
nice pe beautiful people.
Uh, next question from Bellana WGA.
Um, inter species time, space, time.
Dear fellow warrior,
as far as I understand, time is a
different measurement for each species.
Is there a fixed space time? If so, how
is it defined? Constell no does uh
constellations in relation to each
other. If so is there is still the
perspective for exact definition. How do
you make appointments without causing a
complete mess? They fearless iris.
I don't understand exactly everything
you say but
why is the question in there?
Is there a fixed spaceime? No spacetime.
Okay.
The continuum of spaceime is infinite
and eternal. It's a flow. And it's a
flow because it's the evolution. It's
constant move. And in this constant
move, you have fight for balance also
between creation and destruction. And
creation is always
winning a little bit pulling it. The
universe is in constant creation in
constant progress progression evolution
golden mean.
So there's not fixed time.
Um
and I think interfering between points
without causing a mess uh you need to
respect the laws of the universe and um
not advised to travel in time. Listen
you know why travel in time to fix a
mistake
when the universe is all about
evolution.
You make mistake for a reason to learn
and to become better to become more
clever.
Develop your instinct, your intelligence
that when you are confronted to the same
uh challenge, you succeed this challenge
and you take the right decision. Why
coming to the past to raise our
mistakes?
um you know, okay, you can go to the
past to stop a murder,
does something that's really
understandable, but then
the person who lives who should have
died, maybe she does something bad, you
know, she you you don't know. It's all a
question of perspective.
Um, I try to go fast in the questions
then I can answer as much as possible.
45 minutes. Okay, we we get this.
Um, Marott,
how are you? Try it.
Dear Elena, thank you for your
dedication to help us better understand
life. Since
it is the gravity of the planets that
generates time,
how do the ETS regulate their circadian
rhythm? Oh, that's great. When they are
on a ship that is not on the same
gravity as their home world or when they
have to go to many planets regularly.
Such
uh uh oh your question has disappeared.
That's really weird.
Oh, sorry. I got it. Um
as or when they have to go to many
planets regularly such as ambassadors.
Okay.
I love this question and I'm so glad you
asked it, Marott, because that's a great
question. Um
okay
you are from a certain planetary matrix
you have your own circadian circle you
cycle sorry of day and night and so
that's your biology that's your
metabolism and you need to respect it to
be remain healthy.
So your
best solution is to go travel on a ship
with crew members who have the same
psychicadian circle as you. It's not
always the case. So I've seen that in
the federation they respect each other's
cycle
and
the person will go to sleep and rest
when according to their cycles from
their own planet and then they remain
healthy.
because they're not going to have jet
lag constantly, you know. So, wherever
you go, you still are on your
psychicadian
circle cycle.
Um,
and so are the ambassadors, you know.
Um, so that's that's it really. That's
it.
Arisism librarian. Hello. How are you?
Thank you for all your hard work, Elena.
Dearest, who are the guardians of time
to protect it from unethical medling?
The creator,
the creator itself,
the universe itself has laws. And
there's not anyone someone making these
laws and guarding them. It is part of
the construct the dynamic equation of
the universe. It's when you we talk
about laws or ethical laws of the
universe. It's in fact scientific laws,
mathematical laws or um how to say
um mathematical
um geometrical laws.
uh that
keeps the the creation together.
So if you infringe them, you disrupt the
balance of things of creation. That's as
simple as that. And there's no guardians
of laws. It's not nobody created these
laws. Uh these laws are the equations of
the universe that keeps it together.
I suspect the show DC legends of
tomorrow is self-disclosure hinting at
an organization that travels in time to
fix event that have been tampered with
or to alter the cause course of history.
I haven't watched this show. I didn't
know about it. When in your opinion is
it ethical or unethical to me with time?
So I I just answered that. Okay. Thank
you for your question.
Question from Gorana Turkis 17.
So dear Selena, I'm just girishly
curious. Oh, a girly girly question.
I'm scared of the girly questions. Oh my
goodness. I'm just girishly curious if
Thorhan Oh my goodness. was incarnated
with you when you were an Anarch. That's
very cheeky. Did he work with you and
Prince? Thank you as always for your
love to us. Terrau.
So that's a good question. Um yes he was
when I was in Anarch. Um incarnated in
the house of Anu.
Thoran also was incarnated not around
there. He was incarnated in Alia on Alia
in the Altian system on Emiria and he
traveled to Earth um way later later
at the time of Atlantis
from few hundreds of thousand years he
wasn't there on earth I have to say I
didn't say all the time on earth I went
to do other stuff went and back
Um
but yeah, he worked with IA when he
arrived in Atlantis. Of course, he
worked with him. He worked with him. Um
so it's a beautiful, magnificent story
and maybe one day you will read about
it.
Thank you, Gorana.
I know where the cheekiness comes from
in the question. I know what you mean.
Okay, Solaris. Hey, Solaris.
Hi, Elena. If individual ETSs can move
in and out of time, so do they just
measure age based on their physical body
age?
Yes. Yes. Because you when you try time
time traveler, you you you you
travel in your own
time dilation distortion bubble, you
know, you your body doesn't change. Uh I
mean um goes younger or goes older, you
know, you stay as you are time traveler.
Also, what do the regular ET civilians,
non-military, nonfederation personnel
spend time doing?
I don't know.
Thank you. Oh, in
Maric language from Ethiopia. Oh, wow.
Oh, wow. Amalu.
Thank you.
It's beautiful. Oh, it's beautiful
language. Must be very old, very
ancient. Um, oh, what they do? Oh,
that's a long question. Solar is
um
in We will never let you down. I'll go
over the
um
the time when how to spend time, the
leisure time. There's so many things
they do, you know. So, I can't answer
this uh here. I'm sorry. It's too long.
It's too long.
Um,
Greg Prana. Hi, Greg. How are you,
dear Pretty Lina? Oh, thank you. Thank
you for your continued service to
humanity. You must know that many of us
love and support you unconditionally.
My question today is about the parallel
Earth theory. Ah, here we go.
Oh, yeah. Thank you. Thank you. because
I'm going to address it. So, um,
fasten your seat belts.
If I remember correctly, you have
mentioned in the past that there are
higher density planets in the playlist.
Some would say that by this logic, there
could also be a fifth density new Earth
where we will move to when we reach
higher frequencies. Why is this not the
case for our planet? Thank you. Much
love. Yes, there's a misunderstanding.
A planet as a whole like the planets in
the pleades shift into higher density.
Our whole solar system is shifting into
fifth density with whole the whole
planets with it. The whole planets with
it and we will start to see the planets
that are in the fifth density already.
But there's no splitting of anything. We
all move together. The planets of higher
density in the Plleades, they are
there's no other versions of them. It's
them. These planets are one. A world, a
planet, a being. They are one.
And uh the split Earth theory is
something that was introduced by the
QHT, which you know my opinion on this
is not a reliable u thing. So won't go
there but you know my opinion on it.
Um we move as a as one planet we shift
and everything and everyone goes with
it. Um and there will be and the fourth
density people will shift with the
planet as well to be in fifth.
Everything shifts because the matter of
planet the the the particles are going
to vibrate faster.
So everything on it is going to vibrate
faster in a faster density.
All life forms, everything the rocks
will start to to to vibrate faster. A
shift of density of a star system comes
from the star from the sun and the sun
by quantum entanglement with work on the
the the heart of the planet and
everything which is already shifting.
You see time is experienced as faster.
So um that's what I know about this this
theory. Thank you for this question.
Now um
Alexin a hi how did nimma savea three
times?
Well, well, well.
Okay.
Nema had a mission to look after.
She would save his life
three actually twice and a third time
happened. It wasn't planned.
She first saved him from a trap that
that Enlil has set around him in a war
in combat
and she managed to get him out of the
trap. He would have died. Second, he was
poisoned
and very sick.
And um she
healed him.
She healed him. All his body was falling
apart. It was horrible to see. The
poison was like
his skin was breaking like his his
members were about to his his limb were
about to to separate. He was in in
intense suffering. It was horrible. Um,
so with some medicine,
she managed to close all his wounds and
and get him out of here and get him to
the nearest medbed technology on board
the ship to to get him regenerated.
Um, that was horrible. And the third
time as well was uh another trap that
had been set for him,
I have to say. And Leil
hated her.
He hated her because she was always
there for Yeah. always.
She never let him down.
And that's why she's
so much sought after and attacked and
but um
yeah
that's the question the answer.
Thank you for asking it
Hans Diana. How exactly is the time
perspective on the great galactic
temporal war which now comes to its end.
Thanks for all you do. Well, the war,
yes, it comes to its end, but it's not
over yet. You know, the the cigar are
still a thing and they're still
fighting, but they are getting weaker
and weaker and weaker weaker. No major
development in that. Um in that u sorry
toran is connecting.
Hi
in the middle of a webinar.
Okay. Um sorry sorry.
Um
what was the question?
time perspective it's um acting on it's
happening on the fifth density time and
okay what do you want to say sorry
Thoran want to say something sorry you
want to say something
okay
tell the people
that you will always all be well
there is not a second planet that will
be made out of this one
this is not what it is meant to be. This
is not how the universe works. As you
explained very well,
the ridiculous claims that a planet
would split into two different
frequencies is unreasonable.
I am tired hearing this. You need to
understand the laws of physics.
The universe is working as such.
The shift as you explained by this word
will take a lot of time
but it is progressive as evolution is as
you said you listen to my webinar.
Yes. And continue.
I am telling these people who listen
that they are all lucky because they are
living the times
that will be made historical
and the humanity of earth will be
remembered
as heroes
who set the course for their children
for a harmonious world in a safe future.
You do not wait for us to come and tell
you what you have to do. You do not wait
for us to tell you what is behind the
curtain of the dark ones.
You need to work on yourselves to
perform your evolution.
You will set yourselves free. You have
already started.
This is only the beginning.
I am proud of you humans.
Let the Earth Alliance take care of the
dark factions of the hidden governments.
You have not to worry about this. Just
resist as sovereign individuals
and be proud of who you are. Focus on
your mission.
Thoran
high command
XL6.
Thank you.
Wow. But that wasn't expected.
That wasn't expected.
Wow.
What about that?
He's still listening. He's still
listening. He's still listening.
Um,
incredible.
Another question. um
the the statics of this it's it takes a
while to um ease down to recalibrate to
my my my statics of this body. So, um,
for a few minutes, I'm going to be a
little bit like, um, recalibrating my my
thought.
Okay. Now, FG37,
how are you,
dear? When people from other
civilizations who look like us come live
among us and or help permanently or
occasionally like Valor for example,
how can they live among us with
technology?
When you go to them, you need a belt
that or without technology. You need a
belt that helps you to be at higher
level. How do they operate on the planet
without technology? Thank you for
everything you do. Well, they have bells
and some of them um have frequency
modulators. Um and some have
that's a special thing that only
diplomats have it. It's it's in their
brain. They have a frequency modulator
that will recalibrate the frequency rate
of their bodies. But you need a lot of
training and to do this to have this and
not everyone can have it. Um
most of the time they have a either um
um a frequency belt or device like a
triorder that they wear or they carry?
Um next question by
Eina are all beings that are in 5D or
higher densities ethical and
trustworthy? Oh no, no. There's the
people like us. There's everything. I
thought to be at that level means one is
spiritually evolved and pure-hearted.
Love and gratitude for all you do. Yeah.
Um
the Galactic League of Merchants, they
span between different densities.
Um, of course, when you are of higher
density, your consciousness is more
aware and more advanced, more open, more
connected because the consciousness is
more connected to the universe and
source. You you are wiser.
But it doesn't take away the
the personality
life trials and you know and uh I don't
know anger
um envy I don't know sadness
they have these things they are they are
beings with heart and feelings but for
sure feelings like
violent murder or abuse. It's kind of
not there anymore. It's very rare. It
doesn't follow. It doesn't follow, you
know. Um that stays in the lower
densities. So, but that I'm talking
about the generality. Then you have, you
know, fifth density, sixth density
people who are cheeky, you know, and do
cheeky stuff. So, depends on the
culture, the species and
all the things.
Question by Yan.
Could you please illustrate with
concrete example how the ongoing
galactic temporal war operates? For
instance, what changes did the
Federation or the dark faction make in
the past and what impact do they change
have today or in the future modified
event alter memories of past event?
Thank you. Well, um on a concrete level
um the dark fleet hasn't
um sign any
agreement of mergence with the Nebu
Empire, the Nebu forces. There were
always agreements of interest but they
haven't merged their armies.
Um so the threat why because the dark
fleet has been evacuated from earth and
the neighbors have been dismantled
gone. So this has been undone. the the
the the story line I like better to
employ the story line because the story
line can be in the time field as well as
on linear time the story line that story
line stopped was killed was boom stopped
so concretely there's no galactic
tyranny now u incoming galactic tyranny
there is no so that would be what I said
concretely what
Um,
Maria, hello Elena. Past, present, and
future exist at the same time. If so,
your DNA already has three, four, or
five active strand. We just need to
leave that future in the present. Any
advice? Thank you.
Okay,
I understand.
Um, let me read the start of your
question to make sure it's the right
thing.
Okay.
Past, present, and future existing at
the same time in the time field means
the you at in the past
is a different person as you now. That
is a different person as you in the
future. Not it's the same person don't
get me wrong but not the same in a way
that you've changed and you will change
you will evolve as evolution.
So you exist in this time field as
different versions of yourself at
different stage of your evolution. That
is why the natural laws of the universe
do not
allow to go back in time to modify
evolution
because evolution is built on mistakes
and wanderings and wonderings and
challenges and and that's evolution.
So
the the you in the past yes hasn't
learned as many lessons as you have now.
Um,
regarding the strands of DNA,
um, you can activate them at any moment.
Um,
I'm going to
use this.
So, um,
no not going to waste time.
Okay.
What about the strength of dealing? That
is something um
uh quite important.
Of course, when we evolve in
consciousness, we are activating
things in our DNA that are unactive
strings and
um bonds of ehydrogens that have been
cut.
what it is about. A DNA
module
is a power generator. It's an antenna.
Okay? So, you have a a coil with two
two wires.
And these two wires
when they are activated by frequency or
by consciousness,
they vibrate.
they emit a signal. Okay,
you need a power plant that is based on
the two coil like the Tesla technology.
If that you refer to that two coils,
two wires, a coil with two wires, okay,
that cross like this, that's a DNA.
The it crosses in another way because
it's an organic power plant.
So, it's always two strands. Always two
strands,
but each strand, each wire
is made with several little ones.
And regarding the species, regarding
your DNA heritage, you have more or less
pairs of what I call strings around
two coils. Goes by pair. You have two
strands with either
two, six,
4, 12, 10,
different strings.
That is the misconception about
different strands of DNA. DNA has two
strands
and the multiplicity of them is not the
number of strand in the module but is in
the number of strings on the strands.
That is what it is about.
a lot to say about the um you know a lot
to say
had my time with it. Um
Mark Davis aloha Elena, what movie is
your favorite about time? Mahalo Nui
Aloha. Oh.
Oh my goodness. I don't know about time.
I don't really watch movies, but um
except Star Trek.
Um
Doctor Who. I like Doctor Who because
it's funny. Um but it take me off guard.
I wouldn't answer, but straight away I
like Doctor Who because it's funny, but
it's not disclosure at all. At all at
all. It's really comedy. Um,
I've recently watched a movie. It's
called The Alien Code.
Alien Code. Um, it's really interesting.
Really interesting. Um, so it's actually
a good one. Um, but then there are many
other ones.
Bye, Mark. Um now, um Angelina Mater,
hello, how are you? Hi, Lena. Thank you
for all your hard work. A few years ago,
IA mentioned some tortured beings under
Iraq. Have they been freed and sent back
to source as only he could do that?
He hasn't told me about this. What
happened to these um
these uh these beings? So, I don't know.
I couldn't answer the question. Um
I try to remember at the time what um
what was
becoming of them.
I think they were about to be liberated,
freed. I don't remember.
Well, sorry for that. Um but he would
have told me I think he would have told
me if he would have liberated them. So I
think he he hasn't. They are still
there.
Jim, hi Jim. Hi, beautiful Elena. What
more can you tell us about awakening
scientists in stasis? What are they
doing now? Great question. Thanks for
everything, dearest Elena. Oh, so um
some are still in stasis, but the
consciousness they have all merged with
their consciousness is done, you know.
So, it's just avatars. Okay. And they
interconnect with their consciousness
into these avatars. That means they
entangled at any moment they can embody
these and
uh stand up and walk. The thing is
it's still dangerous. It's still
dangerous. The deep state has still a
little bit of power. It's like for
disclosure. You need to be very cautious
because the deep state can twist this
around.
um you know um and attack these people
who waking up from stasis
when the time is right. When the time is
right
question by Liba hey
how are you? Hello. Hey, Lena. How are
you? I just want to ask you about
whether or not parallel realities exist.
Yes, that's the parallel universes. Uh
the the dimensions/ universe
um in which we have different lives and
different events talking place. No, no.
As I told you, you have only one you and
what is mistaken for different uh
realities or parallel reality is in fact
a vision, a perception from the a place
of the linear time of this. And this is
the time field
many you existing at the same time.
That's it. Um, I'd also love to hear
you, but it's not it's
simultaneous, but it's not, you know
what I mean? Um,
it's a field.
Everything is equidistant from
everything. It's, um, ah, how do you say
that? Um, I also love to hear your
thoughts on deja vu and mandela effects
and to your knowledge, what happened
during these moments. Thank you much
love. That is good. Um,
you know, it's like the Mandela effect.
It's it's it comes down to the same
thing. Um,
you have the possibility
when you are free in the field to
connect to any moment in time. And
sometimes
wild entanglements happen.
And you are going to
tangle entangle with an event in a very
near future
because you're in a state of
consciousness. You're quite quite
conscious and you you just entangled to
it and like it happened like nearly like
an accident
a crack an accident and you see the
future as it is the present you know and
it's like this
this impression and that's how it works
that's how it works
um
I hope now you you You've by then you
are able to project your consciousness
your awareness out of gravity and
imagine yourself in this quantum field.
It's you know I advise you I suggest
that you do this uh people as a
meditation uh times to times imagine
yourself in a quantum field and you see
all the other versions of yourself.
What about that?
Donali Schaffer. Dear Elena. Oh, 10
minutes left. Do we When do we get all
our memories back? It feels like I am
never playing with enough information to
make really good decisions. Thanks.
Um,
the memories are not gone. They are
somewhere. They're just disconnected.
All the memories,
all the thoughts, all the experience,
it's recorded, it's stored
somewhere
in your field, your personal field like
the time field of the universe. You have
your personal field where everything is
stored, all the memories. It's just that
the brain, the mind needs to disconnect
for health,
you know. Um he explained this to me
when I was in the mad kahal.
When you have too much information at
the same time in your brain, your
biological brain, it produces too much
chemical that it poisons your brain. So
that's why the brain has this safety of
storing data
for the vivid memory not to be
saturated.
That's only what it is about. But you
can access it whenever you want. You
know, hypnosis does that. But you can do
it on yourself.
Um it's there. It's just it's not
erased. Memory erased doesn't exist.
It's memory disconnection. Also, you
can't erase a memory. It's in the field.
It's been created. It's done. Memories
are the past. The past of your thoughts,
of your experience. It's in the quantum
field. You cannot destroy something that
has passed into the quantum field
unless you travel physically to the past
and change something that it just
vanishes. But that you can do that. But
I mean
erasing a memory
it's was impossible.
You know what I mean?
Jeanu Bellow. Hey Janu.
I need water.
In the spaceships you have traveled in
as well on the as on the Nibiru,
was there weightlessness or artificial
gravity? Is this artificial gravity
equivalent to that of planet Earth?
Um, how is it produced? Electromagnetic
device. Thank you and see you in France.
I love this question. Okay.
So when you're in a ship um there is
artificial gravity that is produced by
um so you know the ship has distortion
field technology that is produced by
magnets and uh heated mercury.
This creates a local gravitational
field.
Then the habitat of the ship is
automatically regulated by well
automatically and you can play on the
regulation of this with a system in the
ground that is going to regulate the
gravity, the pressure
uh composition of the atmosphere. Of
course that's different mechanism at
play but there's an artificial gravity
that is calculated on the the race that
is genetically interface with the ship.
You know it ship can be each ship can be
uh
navigated by people who constructed that
ship the culture and then interfaced
with their DNA their genetics to the the
ship to the controls and also to the AI
of the ship. So also everything else is
accordingly to who they are. The
gravity, the the the
magnet resonance of the habitat, the
atmosphere, everything. So when but when
you're a visitor on these ships
like me,
you are not in your gravitational
environment. So, you need a grav sorry a
frequency belt
or um
suit and something happened to me on
Venus when I was on Venus. We were
talking about Venus earlier on. Um it
occurred that my gravity belt wasn't
well regulated to the
magnetism electromagnetism of Venus and
the gravity of Venus which is was
different. So, I was served a liquid to
drink.
And this liquid uh I don't know what it
did, but it recalibrated my body that it
would fit the gravity on Venus.
It was a like a thick creamy blue
liquid. U
clear blue, I don't remember. Yeah, kind
of creamy grayish blue. Um and uh didn't
taste really good, but um that's what I
am experienced.
Um
okay, let's go. Victoria Nagazaki.
Hello Victoria
10. We managed to arrive to 10. Hello
beautiful Elena. A lot of people on the
internet are talking about Anis the
third brother of Enki and Enlil and
about Alalu the first Anunnaki who came
to earth.
I think they got that from Sichin right
because that's not the case. That's not
right. I would like to know what you
think.
Thank you
in advance with great respect.
Um
yes. Okay. you want next time I come to
Japan. Yes, I'll make an announcement.
Okay. Um
no, I hasn't told me about these things.
So, um and I didn't know there was all
these discretion you don't follow any
online. I don't have time. So, I don't
know. So, um I would have told me about
these things. So, um I'm not able to
give an answer to this.
Um,
Johnny G. Hi Lena, thank you for your
time. You talked about Blu from another
timeline.
Do you mean that Blu is from future or
past?
When did I say that?
Oh, not timeline. Universe. Universe.
Yes. Uh the the blu was brought by the
nebu from another universe, another
bubble universe, another dimension. Yes.
Um that's it.
Um
Shantal. Oh yes. Okay. Okay. Shantal
Bas.
Dearena, it is interesting that when we
are in a state of bliss, the notion of
time and space disappears. Yes. You're
in a time field.
Time space consciousness time space
consciousness
eternity infinity oneness.
That's what bliss is experiencing these
three things.
There is just a reality of the moment
when where you feel complete, free,
connected and peace. At peace our time
and space a construct of the mind
vanishing as we raise frequencies. Thank
you always and much love. Oh, very
enlightened question. Enlightened
question. Are time and space a construct
of the mind vanishing as a raise
frequencies?
I would say
time and space are not a construct of
the mind. But time and space are
experienced by the mind differently
as we raise frequency.
That's what I would say.
It's a marathon questions.
Edlin USA,
greetings, Elena. How can we in the
present recreate our past for a brighter
future? Thank you.
I spoke about how to modify the past to
modify the present.
The secret is to modify the present
directly. You have this power with your
thoughts. Your thoughts emit
electrical impulses that are carrier
waves that carry information. And this
electrical impulse is going to
entangle interfere with the hologram of
reality.
And the information that will be carried
by this impulse
will imprint the hologram and alter it.
Visualize, think how you want this world
to be and and change it by the the
simple strength power of your thought.
You don't need to go in the past to
change the present. You have the power
to change the present now and make the
future you want.
Listen, uh we nearly touch time. So um
I am going to oh Corin I'm going to
answer your question.
Corin Huer does the notion of time which
passes depends only on the time it takes
a planet to revolve around the sun
therefore on the planet or which we live
or it on its frequencies
both. Um
it's all about experience. That's the
experience of time that depends on the
the speed of the cycle, the orbital
cycle and also on the speed of vibration
of matter slash the density.
When you're happy, time flies. Yes, we
spoke about that. But contrary,
everything seems endless. Huge thank you
for everything beautiful, so full of
compassion. Thank you, Corin. And I um
give you back the compliment to you as
well.
Well,
we arrived at the end of this these
three hours
and uh it's me to to pick a question.
So, um
Elena Oh, this one just
caught my mind and I'm going to answer
because it's calling to me. Kristoff E.
Dear Elena, what is eternity?
My gratitude for your commitment to
serving humanity with love from the
Netherlands.
This will be the last um answer. So,
what is eternity?
Eternity
is a tangent.
It goes to a point
of ending
without never touching it.
It goes so close, so close but never
touches it. And same
about the point of beginning.
It will never touch the point of
beginning because there was never a
point of beginning. Point of beginning
and a point of ending are abstract.
And eternity now it's not a line, it's a
field.
Eternity is about time.
Our souls are eternal.
Sure, there are cycles because they
incarnate
to evolve. But when they finish the
cycle, when they feel the moment is
right, they return to source.
We remerge with creator
with all that we have learned and
experienced and we merge back to the
creator
and the creator shoots again.
Consciousness
can be you again starting a new cycle
can be
someone else can be something else.
As we go, we approach source, we lose
individuality.
Same as as when we come from source, we
embrace ini individuality
through our journey down through matter.
Source radiates outwards from the
highest density towards the lowest
density. that
what is
above can influence what is under but
not the contrary.
Eternity
is also cycles but these cycles are of
coming back to source and being shoot
again are also included
in a nonending
and non-binning
time.
Eternity
is the field, the quantum time field.
And I encourage you to through your
meditation, through experience,
to lift your consciousness out of your
body.
And once you're out of it, contemplating
space,
immerse yourself in the knowing to be in
the quantum time field,
in the quantum time space and in one in
the one consciousness.
Be the one consciousness.
Be the field.
Be the infinity.
Be eternal. be infinite,
be one.
And on these words,
my beloved ones
from all my heart,
from the heart of an old soul who came
to earth 400,000 years ago
and has been coming back to help you and
guide you and be your friend.
I am wishing you
to see
the power
that you have.
The power that you have, it's your
consciousness.
You are beautiful.
You are eternal. And you are one with
creator.
See you next
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Heat up here.