hello i'm randall carlson and i would like to
welcome you to a very special episode of after
school i'm a designer and builder by profession
but have for many years been an avid investigator
into the marvels and mysteries of this amazing
world we inhabit i would like to invite you
to join us here on a journey into the realm of
sacred number and symbol and the forms patterns
and cycles of both space and time in which these
numbers are embedded today thanks to the talented
team at after school we'll take a peek behind
the veil into the ancient symbolism of sacred
number that still exists as part of our everyday
lives the animation format employed here is a
powerful medium for conveying the essence of this
knowledge and so without further ado let us begin
so what is the universal language it's symbolism
it's it's number and symbolism and form and
number symbolism and form are universal regardless
of the spoken tongue uh which one happens to have
been brought up in and hopefully in the next
hour hour and a half i'm going to be showing   you examples of this so that you can see for
yourself what actually the universal language of
of geometry and symbolism actually means so we're
going to jump right into it here and talk about
sacred numbers embedded in everyday phenomena
these are the things that we all pretty much
think about and use on a daily basis without ever
really pondering the fact that there's actually   deep symbolism hidden within them we measure
our life in terms of days of 24 hours referred
to as a tropical or solar day and it turns out
that 24 of these hours are 1404 minutes this is
one of the key numbers within the ancient canon
of numerical cosmology that the ancients used
to basically design and create their world
the 440 minutes equates to 86 400 seconds
so if you just listen to these numbers look at
them and let them kind of soak into your brain
once you've gotten into this as a as a actually a
system a methodology of transmitting information
these numbers are actually carriers of information
because each number stands for meanings beyond
just the apparent ones so we see 1440 minutes
is equal to 86 400 seconds and a twelve hour
span of time which is usually represented
on the the clock uh 720 minutes which equals
forty three thousand two hundred seconds so
just look at those numbers you'll think that
obviously forty three thousand two hundred
is half of eighty six thousand four hundred
the fourteen hundred and forty we're gonna
we're gonna counter that number again   here momentarily so these are just examples of
some of the time measures how we think about time
in our particular culture space measure we talk
about a foot we talk about uh of 12 inches we
talk about a square foot you'll notice that the
square foot has the same repetition of digits 144
as the 24 hours does all we do is we tack a zero
on that we have the number of minutes in a day
we have a cubic foot equaling 1728 i want
to call your attention to the one square
yard which is 1296 inches as it turns out we
could stick a zero on the end of that we have
12 960 years which turns out to be an
awesomely important span of time in terms of
some of the great cycles that affect this planet
and and that's what we're going to be getting to
uh geometry everybody knows that a circumference
of a circle is divided into 360 degrees and that
360 degrees of arc because each degree
is subdivided into minutes of arc there
was then 60 times 360 as it says there
are 21 600 and then you'll notice the 21
600 minutes of arc equals 1 million 296 000
seconds of arc that's a mighty fine subdivision of
a circle that would be used mostly by astronomers
to measure the motion of distant stars but notice
that number one million two hundred ninety
six thousand and you'll see that it's the same   number just raised by three orders of magnitude
as the number of square inches in a square yard
okay now another thing you might notice about most
of these numbers from 1440 to 8640 43 200 144 1728
36 1296 is that they all kabbalistically
add up and reduce to the single digit 9.
notice that all of them pick any one of them
other than say with the exception of 24 but 1440
adds and reduces to a single digit nine 1296
you'll notice the same thing one and two and
nine and six is eighteen which adds to a nine
okay so have you if you're taking notes write
these down or make mental notes of these numbers
because these are the numbers we're going to be
encountering now as we go progress through
this through this journey here into the hidden
mathematics so we will start by looking at how
some of these same numbers and other numbers
are associated with the measures of geometry
and here we have what i refer to as the alphabet
of sacred geometry and these are the simplest
forms these are the polygons you have a circle
which is actually not a polygon but we have an
equilateral triangle a square and a pentagon   and each of these can be measured by the
number of degrees that determine the angles
of the sides so for example we look at a circle
which is just a special case of an ellipse with
eccentricity of zero we've covered this already
so let's go right to the equilateral triangle
and we'll see it's 60 60 and 60 which equals 180
degrees again notice that we've got the number 9
recurring we go to the square which is 4 times
90 degrees the total number of degrees defining
the square is 360 the same as the circle the same
as the measure of a circle and we measure the
polygons by essentially measuring the angles of
the vertices or the corners so then likewise with
the pentagon each of the angles between successive
edges is 108 degrees so you multiply the 108 times
5 and you get 540. again notice everything adds
up to nine for some strange reason 108 is going
to turn out to be a very important number
it's a lunar number as you're going to see   108 anybody know what metal has an atomic weight
of silver that i mean atomic weight of 108 yes
that's right it's silver very good all right
so let's get into some of the solid tetrahedron
is this form right here and it's composed of four
of the equilateral triangles so we have as it says
here there's four triangular faces four times 180
is 720 degrees that is the total angular measure
of this particular geometric form this is known
as one of the platonic solids or regular polyhedra
polyhedra means multiple faces and the regular
polyhedra is the family of five there's only five
that have the same shape or the same polygonal
face in this case the equilateral triangle and
then we will move on to the cube and the cube is
six faces and they're each square and we saw that
that each of those square faces had 360 degrees
6 times 360. the important thing is to grasp that
the total number of degrees in this form is 2160
2160 and we're going to find out that that number
actually turns out to be pretty significant in
the measure of other parts of time and space
then we'll go to the octahedron
and it has eight triangular faces
this is our octahedron right here and they're
all you'll notice that so far the the tetrahedron
and the octahedron are both composed of
triangular equilateral triangular faces
and essentially if you look at the difference
between the tetrahedron and the octahedron   you could just imagine that if we could take
the tetrahedron and split it along an edge
and insert a fourth triangular face it would cause
it to flatten out somewhat and it would give us
the top half of the octahedron and likewise we
could insert a fifth equilateral triangle in
here and it's going to give us the icosahedron
which i'll show you in a minute if we tried to   insert a sixth one though we discovered that the
whole thing flattened out into two dimensions so
that wouldn't work as far as enclosing
space so in any case notice we're seeing   a recurrence of this number that we saw
1440. remember we saw that number back right
right here the number of minutes in a day so
let that that relationship sink in the number
of minutes in the time that it takes our earth to
spin exactly once on its axis relative to the sun
happens to be the same number of
degrees that define the octahedron
and that's actually what we're talking about then
when we're talking about a tropical or solar day   we're talking about one exactly one rotation
of the earth on its axis relative to the sun
okay then we have the icosahedron
which is 20 faces all equilateral triangles
you can see if you look at the vertex of this
thing you see that there are five faces clustered
around each vertex so if we were to split an edge
insert another triangle what it would happen is
it would flatten out into a hexagon a flat hexagon
with six equilateral triangles about its center in
any case there are 20 of these triangular faces 20
times 180 is 3600 so again we have one of our
nines and then our final is our dodecahedron
my favorite shape this is what plato
referred to the dodecahedron as being   the the shape of the universe itself
the dodecahedron you'll notice has uh
12 faces 20 vertices whereas the icosahedron has
20 faces and 12 vertices so they're duals of each
other we could actually suspend this icosahedron
if the dodecahedron was hollow we could put it
inside we would discover that each corner
of the icosahedron coincided with the center
of the pentagonal face of the doe decahedron okay
each pentagonal face as we found out was a each
edge was 108 5 times 108 540 12 times 540 as it
says is 6480. so again we've got a the number nine
redundantly occurring over and over again
in these measures okay 6480 turns out to
be a critically important number as well as
you're going to see as we proceed along here
oh and then we have the star tetrahedron which
would be two tetrahedrons interlaced and i don't
have one of those today but if you can picture
a tetrahedron like this and then one like this
interlaced it gives you this what's known
as sometimes the star tetrahedron or the   stellated octahedron it is composed of two
tetrahedrons each of 720 so here again now
you're seeing the repetition of this same
number 1440 being the measure of the of the uh
star tetrahedron okay so now we're going to talk
about time measures the first thing we're going to
look at is astrological time cycles i don't
know how many of you have studied astrology
but in this particular scheme of time the total
duration of the processional cycle which is 25
920 years this is the motion of the earth on its
axis like this or you could think of it like this
the axis of the earth actually forms sort of
an hourglass motion a long slow period of um
of rotation it's some you could consider earth's
third motion next to its first motion which is
the daily rotation of the earth on its axis
its second motion which is the orbit of the
earth around the sun and its third motion
which is the precession of the earth's axis
the daily the the diurnal or daily rotation of
the earth on its axis gives us the day-night cycle
which is obviously of critical importance to our
life down here on earth the orbit around the sun
also is likewise of critical importance because
that's the yearly cycle the third motion is what
the ancients refer to as the great ear and it's
been measured by astronomers at slightly over 50
seconds of arc of motion per year which actually
puts the astronomically determined number slightly
less than this one but we don't know that that's
necessarily constant for the whole cycle in any
case the the ancient number that was typically
attributed to this great year cycle was 25
920 years that great year was considered to
be analogous to our annual year and just as
the annual year was divided into four seasons
of spring summer winter and fall likewise the
great year was divided into four great seasons
symbolized by the four fixed signs of the zodiac
the bowl the lion the eagle and the man or the
angel if you divide 25 920 by four to determine
the duration of each season you'll discover that
it's 6480 years which is interesting because
four hundred 6400 eighty years as
you recall was the total measure   of the dodecahedron so here we
have this same number linking
the measure of space in terms of the dodecahedron
6480 degrees and the season of the great year
which was considered to be profoundly
important to ancient cultures all over the
world who had various ways of representing
this four-fold division of cyclical time
all right then we have from the ancient
caldeans we have what was known as the   cerro cycle which was 3600 years so we see a
repetition of that number the 3600 if you re
recalling and are taking notes is the number of
degrees measuring the icosahedron then we have
the the decans you'll notice that a platonic month
which is 1 12 1 12 of the great year right there
you divide that number by 12 you get this number
2160 and that number you may recall depending on
how good your memory is is the number of degrees
measuring the cube two thousand one hundred and
sixty and then you'll notice the two decans of
the ecliptic is or 20 degrees of the ecliptic
is fourteen hundred and forty the number of
degrees in the octahedron and one deckhand
or 10 degrees for any of you who've studied
astrology you know that the deckhands are   important to astrological determinations one
deckhand of 10 degrees then takes 720 years
and so here we have all five of the platonic
solids represented in these particular time cycles
and over here i'm going to mention that
ancient cultures all over the world used
to run two calendars successfully a secular
calendar which is typically like our modern
calendar of 365 and one quarter days and then
they would have a sacred calendar of 360 days
and in five days intercalated they would
call it typically they would do whether
it was the greeks or the egyptians or even the
mayans ancient cultures all over the world had
similar uh traditions of setting those five days
aside and they were considered to be unlucky
and so no really no work no activity nothing
nobody ever tried to do anything on those days
they would just take those days off five days off
then they would resume again and pick up their
sacred year of 360 degrees now the sumerians had a
belief that the year was once actually 360 days in
length and it's somewhere along as a result of
some cosmic catastrophe of some undefined sort
the day was the year was lengthened by five and
one quarter days and so the sumerians who are the
first known culture to mathematically divide the
circle into 360 degrees it is believed that one of
their motives for doing so was they believed that
that circle then could become a model of the year
and each degree then representing one day so what
we have now is a synchrony going on in that if the
year the idealized or sacred years 360 days then
what we have if you actually picture it is that
the earth is describing a circle in its orbit but
then in each degree of motion around that circle
it's turned once on its axis so what we have
there is a synchronization of this cosmic motion
representing these numbers so in any case the
ancient cultures would reckon time measure by
360 days according to the sacred calendar
and by doing so they could then divide
that 360 days of the sacred year into
subdivisions such as this right over here
and we'll just run through that very quickly
you'll notice that one deckhand turns out to
be 10 days within the sacred calendar and that's
exactly 14 400 minutes so here we have the same
numbers recurring again you'll notice though that
the number the symbolism of the number is not lost
or the system of the the symbolism of the
number is consistent irrespective of its
order of magnitude so in other words you could say
the square of 12 being 144 has the same symbolism
as 144 times 10 or 144 times 100 as you have right
here or even 144 times a thousand again referring
back to the book of revelations there's a verse
in there uh referring to the 144 000 redeemed of
the earth and we'll get to that uh here shortly
that's an interesting quote because they have
various ways of embedding these sacred numbers
into the into the various traditions you'll notice
that three decades or one platonic month in the
platonic year was 2160 years but in the sacred
year of 360 days again there's that 43 200. so and
go down here the one platonic season of 6480 years
129 600. so if you're taking notes and writing
these down you're going to find it you're
writing down the same numbers over and over again
simply raised to different orders of magnitude
okay this is just a little graphic that depicts
this processional motion that i'm talking about
here this motion right here that is generally
assumed by most astronomers to be primarily
induced onto the earth by by the moon secondarily
by the sun and then also a contributing factor by
the planets so it's almost you could almost think
of this processional motion of the earth's axis
as being the uh the vector summation of
all the gravity forces of the solar system
acting on the earth causing it acting see when
the planet rotates on its axis and this is a
critically uh critical factor
as it rotates on its axis
it spreads out towards the middle its equatorial
diameter is greater than its polar diameter and
that in fact is critical to the earth
maintaining uh axial stability so that
it's not doing this in its orbit around the sun
because if it was doing that uh it's likely that
higher life would have never evolved in the
first place but due to the fact that it spins
it spreads out so that the diameter of the equator
is 26 miles greater than the diameter of the pole
the sum total of all the gravity forces impinging
upon the earth from moon sun and planets
acts upon that bulge as if it was a flywheel and
is actually pulling it around pulling it around
and it's that that that leads to the great year
and uh what it does is over a period of half the
great year one million or uh 12 960 years is it
reverses the seasons so that if we were able to
jump in a time machine and go back 12 960 or ahead
12960 we would find that everything was reversed
if we would keep the same gregorian calendar in
place the seasons would have been reversed so that
winter would be july and summer would be in fact
and then what we would see is that hemispherically
like we know that when it's winter in the northern
hemisphere it's southern it's summer in the   southern hemisphere well those seasons would be
reversed they flip it's a back and forth it's an
oscillation between uh the two hemispheres of
the earth over a period of of of 12 960 years
this shows that the wheel of the great year
with all of the ages the astrological months as
they're known and if we were to place ourselves
right at this position right here where it says
zero years bp bp means before present and it also
is 25 920 years so what has been happening is
that the vernal equinox the oppo a hypothetical
point in space occupied by the sun when day and
night or the exact same duration that vernal
point is moving through space as a result of
this axial motion of the earth and ancient
peoples would go to great lengths to try to
observe and predict that motion so they would set
up structures oftentimes on a very large scale
that would be oriented to certain points in space
so that one could from certain vantage points such
as the center of a ringed megalithic structure
for example or the center of a temple that had
an axial orientation to a certain point on the
horizon one could make my new observations of this
slowly shifting uh vernal equinox or for example
the solstices the vernal equinox and the solstices
are two lines in space that are right angles to
each other i'll show you a graphic in a minute
but in any case as we go around this wheel this
great wheel here this wheel of this cosmic wheel
what we're going to see is that each of these is
a zodiacal sign we have here pisces we have here
aquarius so now the vernal equinox is poised
it's it's moving out of the star constellation of
pisces moving into the star
constellation of aquarius   and so we say that roughly for the last
2000 or if we want to be precise 2160 years
the vernal equinox has been transiting the
constellation of pisces and therefore we've   been in the piscean age prior to that was aries
prior to that was taurus we find that the uh the
beginning of modern recorded history goes back to
the taurian age we can essentially express all of
recorded human history between the
the latter part of the taurian age
through the age of aries the age of pisces
and now into the age of aquarius right
okay if we go back we'll notice though that
the numbers here are the same numbers the same
family of numbers we've been looking at here
2160 4320 6480 8640 10800 we saw the number
108 i called your attention to that when i was
asking you what was the atomic weight of silver
and which metal i mean which which
astronomical object is silver associated with
the moon yes 12 960 puts us
exactly on the opposite end of the
equinoctial axis and then we see it right angles
to each other we have this is the autumn spring
axis and this is the summer winter axis and
they're at right angles to each other and   the whole thing is rotating you've got a picture
that this propeller is rotating counterclockwise
so that in 6480 years taurus will be
have moved down to the zero point okay
we've seen this so this is just a recap of
those same numbers and you will notice 8640
the number of seconds in one day you'll notice
that in a half a day 43 200 well if you go back to
the dawning of the age of aries
three hundred and twenty years ago
and these are just more interesting ways
that these numbers show up if you take
twenty five thousand nine hundred
twenty seconds and set each each   second corresponding to one year of the great
year you'll discover it's exactly 432 minutes
25 920 hours in turn is 1080 days and 25 920 days
is equal to 72 years in the sacred calendar which
is interesting because i think if you most uh
determinations of the average human lifespan
right now in history is about 72 years
so you could think of a human lifespan
as being equivalent to one day of the great year
there's an interesting proportional relationship
going on there between the total processional
cycle of 25 920 years and one human lifetime
in the vedas they had various ways
of encoding uh references to numbers
let the brahman hear the praise we utter
this has the four-horned buffalo emitted
four are his horns three are the feet that
bear him his heads are two his hands are
seven in number notice four three two raised
to the seventh power gives you the number of
years in the ancient vedic time span the culpa
4 billion 320 million years which i find to be
suspiciously close to the modern estimate for the
age of the universe which is about four and a half
or the age of the earth rather which is about four
and a half billion years so this was one way they
had of encoding or embedding references to these
sacred numbers in the vedas and this is probably
some of the oldest writings that extent where
these this canon of numerology is is presented
in ancient samaria from the various writings of
historians like um barossas and others and from
the sumerian clay tablets were able
to find that there were references to
ten pre or anti-diluvian kings
what does uh pre deluvian mean
before the flood right so they had this belief
that there were ten kings raining before the flood
and you'll notice the numbers that they ascribed
to each of the kings the rain uh those numbers
now should all be becoming familiar to you you've
seen a bunch of them already there's forty three
thousand two hundred sixty four eight hundred
thirty six you'll notice sixty four thousand
eight hundred is uh presented twice actually three
times the total low forty four hundred and thirty
two thousand years um that's a long span of time
do you think they meant this literally or is this
strictly symbolic and figurative is it possible
that the king could have reigned for 36 000 years
i tend to think it was symbolical but you know it
is interesting that one of the again one of the
universal traditions from ancient cultures is that
before the flood in all the cultures from all over
the world recognized that there was a great flood
or even floods that decimated humanity at various
times but they're all pretty much in agreement
that prior to the flood the human lifespan was   much longer than it is today which i find we've
all heard about methuselah living to be 969 years
right or lamech being 777. it seems that they had
in the biblical ages they seem to have lived about
an order of magnitude greater than our modern ages
which considering you know from my perspective
the things i'd like to get done in this
lifetime i would need at least that many years
in the value piranha which is again one of
the vedas we find verses like this 360 years
according to the human calculation constitute
one divine year wise people know that there
are four yugas in bharata varsa the first
one is krata then follow trata devapara
and kali probably some of you have heard of the
kali yuga that we're supposedly in right now
and suppose the age of darkness
and the age of ignorance
but you'll notice that they they reckon
time they have a they have another the
vedas recognizes a sacred year that they call
or a divine year which is 360 of our years
okay now here's a tabulation of the vedic ages
and you'll notice we'll look first at the total
in human years and we see that the
kali yuga the shortest is 432 thousand
then we go to 864 thousand one million two hundred
ninety six thousand one million seven hundred
twenty eight and four million three hundred
and twenty thousand you'll notice that the   total or the maha yuga the great yuga is
ten times the length of the kali yuga and uh
that's because you'll notice that that
the drapara is twice the trade is three   times and the sake is four times so taking the
original term doubling it then tripling it then
quadrupling it adding those together will give
us 10 times the number we started with but again
notice the number that the vedic ages
begins with 432 000 is the same number
that the sumerian king list ends with so it's
almost as if we have two different traditions but
one system and we see that the sumerians preserve
knowledge about the the um subdivisions of this
yuga time of 432 thousand years and symbolize
these subdivisions by the reigns of these these 10
uh prediluvian kings and then we can see that once
we get to 432 000 years at that point the vedic
cycles kick in and then we have these that follow
and using the divine year of 360 years yields
these this column of numbers and then when we put
the duration into human years it's interesting
each each of the yugas such as the kali yuga
they were all believed to have a a period
of transition into the age then the age itself
and then a period of transition out of the age
and so basically what they did was they took the
the total age you'll notice here the relationship
between the kali yugas the 360 thousand and
the sanja which was the transition in the
sun yamsa which was the transition out are each
one tenth of that adding up to the total of 432
but you'll notice that we we're we've got the same
recurring numbers again now there's 144 000 right
there and then we have that raised by another
order of magnitude so you see how these same
numbers are recurring over and over again uh and i
would suggest that there's a pattern emerging here
and i know that for a lot of people first time
they are confronted with this kind of information
sometimes it's almost too mind-boggling you're
going what the heck is all these numbers mean   uh you know it's just too many numbers to
sort out but what you realize once you start
studying them is that each one of them is
kind of a mnemonic because each number has   a whole collection of phenomena that's associated
with it and it's still in use today i mean how
many people i mean everybody should know that
you know a square foot is 144 square inches i
mean anybody who's a builder a craftsperson an
artist should know basic rules of measurement
the mayan world ages now you notice there
do we see similar numbers the buck tune
144 000 days so it's almost like they took the
same they had the same numbers but they're now
representing smaller cycles but it's the same
numbers representing the cyclical periods within
nature a tune is 360 days and that was the
typical that was the sacred calendar that we
find all over the ancient world and then they had
the five days added to that the five unlucky days
so again we see the same numbers being repeated
redundantly throughout these various traditions
sacred numbers embedded in solar
system architecture i'm only going   to show you a few examples of this to
convey to you the idea the solar orb
well if we measure that we discover its   radius is 432 000 miles which of course
means that its diameter is 864 000 miles
so notice that we measured the sun according
to the human measure of miles and by the way um
what is the origin of the the mile unit
that we use anybody know origin of the mile
origin of the mile it comes from the
latin word mill which means a thousand
so it's talking about a thousand something
what would it be talking about a thousand what
a thousand paces that average 5.28 feet in length
it actually goes back we know that romans were
using a mile there were a thousand paces and they
would lay out rome for example had a city center
and everything was measured outwards from that
city center according to paces and those paces
were um a thousand of them gave the roman
mile the roman pace was a little bit shorter
than the british pace which is where we get our
mile from our mile in fact interestingly and
i'm going to show you a diagram of this shortly
uh stonehenge is 105 the the outer ring of the
sarsonstone circle measures right at about 105.6
feet which makes its one-fifth of a mile or one
150th of a mile i'm sorry that and several other
numbers that we find in megalithic structures in
ancient england suggest that the mile was actually
a unit of measure that was being used as long ago   as four thousand years or longer and we're still
using it today the same unit of measure that
could have been used 4 000 years ago and for that
reason um you know i there and once you begin to
get into and understand um the sacred basis of
our ancient meteorological or measuring systems
you'll realize that if we convert completely over
to the metric system we're going to lose something
very very profound all right remember what was
the length of the kali yuga 432 000 years what
was the length of the dopara yuga 864 000 years
what was the length of a platonic month 1 12th of
the great year anybody remember 2160 years right
the same number of degrees that measure the cube
all right what are we looking at here
anybody recognize that look familiar
the moon has a radius of 1080 miles which gives
it a diameter of 2160. remember i said that
1080 or 108 and it's double 2160 was a lunar
number see this is a clue to you now there are
several references for example um in the sumerian
tradition describing the ark built by zizithrus
which is being described as a cube that makes no
sense you think what kind of a ship is it that
would be described as a cube you know it wouldn't
be very seaworthy a cube right but it's not
referring to an actual ship as we think of it it's
referring to the cubing of the sphere and in this
case the sphere that it's referring to is the moon
which was symbolically considered to be an arc
to many of the ancient cultures that believed
that the earth was periodically destroyed by great
catastrophes so we have the number 1080 and we
have the number 2160. and then we have the earth
you know that's the earth and again because
of the spinning of the earth on its axis
we have this difference between the polar diameter
78.99 or just thinking round number 7900 miles
and the equatorial diameter 7926 so that
creates a 26 mile difference and thank
thank you for that 26 mile difference because
life on earth would be a very chaotic affair
without that bulge we see that the diameter of
a sphere with the same surface area as earth is
7920 miles and also the diameter of the earth
when you take it from if you slice it through
the tropic of cancer through to the tropic of
capricorn that diameter also is about 7 920
so we use 7920 as the sacred number
to represent the earth because
even though the earth varies considerably
between equatorial and polar diameters   we find that at a very significant piercing
through of the earth's diameter from one tropic
to the other tropic turns out to be 7900 miles
we also find that if we take a perfect sphere
that has a the same area the same
surface area as the earth actually has
its diameter would be 7920 miles so
that's the number we use for the earth
which means that its radius is half
that or 3960. and in most books you read
astronomy and so forth when
they're talking in round numbers   about the radius of the diameter of the earth
these are the numbers they use 79 20 and
and 39.60 okay now what i've got here is
evidence for advanced geodetic knowledge
in archaic times what is geo what is geodesy or
geodetic knowledge geodesy is the determination
of the size and the shape of the earth early
in the 19th century such knowledge was acquired
by extensive land surveying and triangulating
over large tracts of the earth's surface since
the 1970s orbital satellites have provided the
most accurate picture of the earth's exact size
and mass distribution any advanced comprehension
of the larger picture of our planet as a suitable
abode for the evolution of higher life requires
knowledge of its size and shape the total mass
of course determines g the gravitational constant
the equatorial bulge is an integral component of
the forces acting to impose rotation and orbital
stability on earth as it wheels about the sun
the relevance of these two basic factors to
the evolution of life cannot be underestimated
ancient master builders understood earth's
fundamental geodetic parameters on a level
not equaled until the advent of modern satellite
surveys how do we know that well probably the most
salient means we have of knowing that is the
great pyramid of chiops itself and there's been
lots and lots of speculation about what the form
or what the function of the great pyramid was some
of it to me is is pretty pretty out there some
of it i think is pretty abstract and speculative
what i've always thought does make the most
sense and has the greatest credibility is the
pyramid is essentially a model of the earth the
northern hemisphere and i'll show you how here
the thing you have to understand when you're
looking at the measurement of the earth in   terms of its size and shape is that we have lines
everybody knows latitude and longitude latitude
is measured north and south of the equator
longitude is the measure around this way
parallels are lines that run
hor the parallel to the equator   and traveling along one of the parallels we
would be displacing ourselves longitudinally
but parallels actually measure you can see the
this parallel here this is probably the arctic
circle it looks to me like about 66 and a half
degrees north so it is parallel to the equator
right so depending on what parallel you are
every line of latitude north and south has
a corresponding parallel and you know that from
the equator to the north pole is going to be 90   degrees and likewise from the equator to the south
pole is going to be 90 degrees of arc then in turn
we have meridian lines which are lines that run
north south but actually measured distances east
and west so that if you travel from one meridian
to the next to another meridian you would have
traveled from east to west every point on the
surface of the earth has a local meridian we
have a local meridian here and it's basically the
way you would find it is if you walked out here i
believe this is generally south isn't it this way
so if we went out here and we looked exactly south
and exactly north and then the zenith overhead
the point 90 degrees up from a flat horizon
and we struck an arc from the south point through
the zenith point to the north pole that arc would
be our local meridian and as the earth turns under
that local meridian we measure all astronomical
motion relative to our point on the surface of
the earth with respect to that local meridian now
you'll notice that as you go through the parallels
the parallels form virtually perfect circles
the meridian lines on the other hand are
not circles because of the flattening   of the earth because of the expansion of the
equator if you draw a line around it this way
this way and cut the earth this way it is not
going to be a circle if you cut it this way it   will be a circle okay that creates very subtle
differences in geometry when you're measuring
a meridian line north to south what happens is
that as you travel north away from the equator
if you were going on a perfect sphere then
each degree of latitude north would have the
same distance but it's not a perfect sphere it's
flattened so as you're moving towards the north
pole the earth is actually flattening out the
earth's radius is shrinking so it's flattening
out what that means is that to to traverse a
degree of arc you have to travel further as
you get away from the equator towards the north
pole okay i'm i'm explaining this because you've
got to understand this to see how the ancients
actually understood how they demonstrated to us
that they understood the size and shape of
the earth with a high degree of accuracy   so again parallels are going to be in circles and
you're going to notice that the biggest circle is
going to be the equatorial circle and as you
travel towards the the poles those circles get
smaller in size so therefore if you took the
meridian lines which would be the dotted lines
the distance between say one degree of meridians
at the equator is going to be greater than that
distance between the same two meridians say at our
latitude here in atlanta which is about 34 degrees
north or further north as you travel further north
those meridian lines converge until you get to the
north pole and then they they meet each other and
have zero distance between them okay this is taken
out of the smithsonian meteorological tables and
what we're looking at here without belaboring this
is you'll notice latitude 0 degrees and you go
through up to 90 degrees and what this is showing
is if we look in the statute miles right there
this says length of one degree of the meridian
so this is the line from equator up to the north
pole well if you look at the first number which
let's see if we can zoom in a little here
you'll notice that at zero when you travel
leave the equator and go to the first degree
north latitude you've gone 68.703 miles
but if you look down here at the very last one
when you traverse that last degree from 89 and you
finally get to the north pole you've traveled 69.4
miles so those degrees have stretched out okay
now this is important to understand how
the ancients were able to demonstrate
to future generations that they understood
the size and the shape of the earth
and then we have one length of one degree of the
parallel if you notice right there i don't know   if you can read it from out there but that says
69.172 miles so think of a circle going around the
earth's equator you've traveled one degree one 360
of that distance around you've gone 69.172 miles
let's go halfway up from equator to north pole
which would be 45 degrees and you see right there
you've gone 49 miles then when you get up
to the pole itself when you're one degree
away from the north pole you only have to go 1.2
miles because those meridian lines have converged
so now the thing to grasp here is that if we're
measuring the size and the shape of the earth
that's going to vary depending on where on
the earth we're making those measurements
this is important because what we
discover is that the ancient peoples   knew this and incorporated into their architecture
so that they would derive units of measurement
that were ultimately based upon the size and
shape of the earth where the structure was
being built now let's take the most prominent
one before we get to that this is geodetic data
and you'll notice here we've got going back
to 1830 which was the first attempt in modern
times to determine the size and shape of the
earth and let's go since that's meters let's go
to something we'll recognize miles
we're talking about the radius here
and you'll notice as you're coming down through
here we get to these last two world grid system
72 and geodetic reference system 80 are the two
that were determined by satellite measurements
and you'll notice that as we come through
here we've got a polar radius in miles and n   equatorial radius in miles and then we have
the difference in the two radii right here
and we assume that as we've come through
we're progressively getting better and   better at measuring the size and shape of the
earth and finally with satellite measurements
we're getting down here and we've determined
that the polar radius for example 3949.8934
3949.8948 what does that
translate into well let's see
in terms of feet that's a difference
of uh oh 250 feet roughly between um
yeah between these two measurements in
other words between the first satellite   measurement and 72 in the second one in in
1980 the difference was about 250 feet safe
the history of man may be far longer and stranger
than we think the great pyramid may indeed not
fit in with what we believe about the past and
the nature of the world thousands of years ago
someone measured the earth with remarkable
accuracy and recorded this information in   the dimensions of the largest and possibly the
oldest stone building on the planet william r fix
generally the age of the pyramid
is given around 4 200 years   it's roughly about the same age as the sphinx
some of you are probably familiar with the however
the re-dating of the sphinx by several geologists
primarily robert shock from boston university
who has studied the weathering of the limestone
composing the sphinx and the surrounding quarry
that the sphinx is situated in and has determined
that the uh that the rock has been severely
weathered by water erosion and of course this giza
plateau has been desert for the last 4 000 years
so it's not likely you're going to find severe
water erosion on the sphinx if it's only 4 000
years old in fact so severe is the water erosion
that it's likely that the sphinx is probably tens
of thousands of years old however robert shock
in most of his public presentations
usually places it at seven to nine   thousand years but he's totally personally he
just uses that because he's deliberately being
very conservative because he's in the academic
community but he's perfectly willing to believe
that it is could be much older than that and i've
discussed the the extent of the water erosion
with him and discovered that he actually hasn't
looked uh in depth at the uh comparable studies of
rates of limestone weathering which i
spent a couple of months about 10 years ago
studying going around the various places
where there were limestones and where   you could see examples of limestone that
had been weathered and had looked at um
read the literature that had been done on
limestone weathering it had concluded that   you know would be a minimum of 20 000 years worth
of weathering and that's a minimum if you took the
sphinx and set it in a climate with rainfall like
say we've been having for the last three months
which would average out to about 45 inches a
year even with rainfall like we've been seeing
here in atlanta in the last three months it would
take the sphinx a minimum of 20 to 30 000 years to
get the level of erosion that raises the question
regarding the great pyramid could it be as old
and i see no reason why not problem here though is
you know that the great pyramid was once covered
in white limestone casing stones highly polished
and according to arabic traditions pretty much all
the arabic traditions and legends about the great
pyramid concur that the outside of the pyramid
prior to the stripping of the casing stones
was covered completely covered in hieroglyphs
and one it just boggles one's mind to contemplate
what might have been written here but clearly
i have a hard time imagining a greater act of
vandalism in all of history than the stripping
of those stones in fact there had been efforts
to get into the pyramid up until the time of
alma moon which was i think around 1200 a.d
but they were completely ineffectual and then
somewhere around the 12th century i forgot
the exact year there was a great earthquake   in northern egypt and it caused most
of the buildings in cairo to collapse
and it also loosened some of the casing stones on
the pyramid which allowed them to get in and pry
those stones loose from the top and all of the
stones were then stripped off and that high
indirect high quality limestone was stripped off
and recarved and used in buildings to rebuild
cairo so i've often thought there's probably
temples somewhere in cairo where maybe
some of those original stones are still to be
found with inscriptions intact of course i have
no idea but i oftentimes thought wouldn't that
be cool anyways they stripped off the stones
and as they stripped them off there
was a lot of rubble that fell down   and buried the bottom of the pyramid which
turned out to be a good thing because it buried
the bottom casing stones from those bottom and
preserved and so from those you know the various
researchers could determine what the original
exact angle of the pyramid was and according   to most calculations it was around 51 degrees 51
minutes 14 seconds i don't know if that level of
accuracy is is credible or not but 51 minutes
51 degrees 51 minutes would be and from there
we can then determine what the geometry of the
pyramid would have been and what its original   height would have been simply by taking the
tangent of of that angle 51 degrees 51 minutes
and knowing the base length one could calculate
what the original height would have been to a   high degree of accuracy so that's been done by
oh four or five different people over the years
j.h cole in 1925 did what's considered to be
the definitive survey of the great pyramid
he was a professional survey who did a very
meticulous survey after they had just cleared
away all of the rubble and he had access to
it he did it under contract to the to the
government of egypt the numbers that i'm about to
show you here are mostly derived from his survey
so what we have here is here's some of the
original casing stones and they sit on a
what's called a sockle which is this base which
was measured to be 55 centimeters in thickness
and of course you got to bear in mind that
this original slope casing stone there was
not it wasn't stepped like that originally it was
a smooth profile and let me okay so here you have
course here you see that the casing stones were
damaged by the rubble falling down but enough of
them were still intact that one could make this
accurate determination of the original angle   here's the sockle which is 55 centimeters thick
and it sits directly on bedrock so it actually
what it does is it creates two ways that one
could measure the height of the pyramid either   with or without the sockle there's also two ways
of measuring the base this is a reconstruction
from a 1991 work on uh pharonic stone masonry
and this shows that outside the corners
which was the the core masonry there are these
sockets and i found one picture showing a socket
this is showing one of the sockets that's
still there that sits outside the core masonry   but based on those sockets they were able to
reconstruct what the original base of the pyramid
would have looked like so here would have been the
51 degrees 51 minutes coming down sitting on the   55 centimeter thick sockle here like this well
what this did was it gave two ways of measuring
the perimeter of the pyramid's base one
could be measured from this point up on   top of the circle the other could be measured
from down here that included the saw so what
you ended up with was two ways of measuring the
pyramid's base well which one was the correct one
well they were both correct i think that they were
actually intending to embody in there that there   were two ways of measuring uh the pyramids base
so what we have is the length of the base on the
sockle which is the shorter of the two up there
it was varied from side to side you'll notice 755
at the smallest to 756 just over at the largest
so there was some variation there was probably
a reason for that variation actually but we won't
get into that because it just gets too technical
for what we're talking about today but the total
of those measured around the four sides would be
3023.139 feet if you're taking notes
that'd be a good number to write down
okay so now let's see what the measure is
around that includes the cycle or the base
and we see that it's each side is a roughly five
feet longer 760 to 761 each side again is a little
different but we get a total of 3043.43 feet okay
so i'm going to over here i'm going to write down
a few numbers that we saw through our radius of
the moon diameter of the moon radius of the sun
diameter of the sun number of seconds in a day would be 432 000 43
200 uh number of seconds and a half a day number
of seconds in a full day 86 400 what were some of
our more other numbers oh yeah 14 40 was 1 79 20
diameter of the earth just so they're up
there in front of you we can refer to them   as we go on here all right so here is
profile the great pyramid with a 51 degree
51 minute angle i've just to make it easy i've
just rounded off the numbers 481 feet in height
that would be not including
the the sockle the base 755.85 i just picked one to use
and there's our 51 degree 51 minute angle
and we find that when we measure measure it
this way it turns out to be almost exactly 11
over 7. there's some other interesting geometry
going on related to the golden section
which i don't intend to get into today   because it makes more sense if you're actually
studying sacred geometry and you're familiar
and you've made these drawings because in a sacred
geometry class just like in the old pythagorean
platonic lodges we draw we draw we draw and
then we eventually build models and that's
the way to really get familiar with this and
get these numbers as part of your consciousness
so i'm not going to get into the
connection with the golden section today   when we measure including the cycle this becomes
our height 482.7575 feet and the base 760.9 feet
okay those are the numbers we're
going to look at for a second here now
if we look at these these are various
estimates we're we're looking at
this one right here the coal height estimate
plus the cycle at 21.6 inches gives a total
of the height above bedrock of
482.757 feet so now we're going to go
back to the earth so we can see how these
numbers link the two we take one square degree
of latitude and longitude at the equator pretend
we're standing at the equator okay we know
that the polar radius now is 13 miles less than
the equatorial radius so what that means is that
the circle this way is shorter than the circle
the biggest circle that defines the earth is
the equatorial circle so a degree of measure
on the equator is going to be the biggest
the longest of any degree we measure anywhere
on the earth the equator okay the north-south is
going to be a little bit shorter and you'll notice
right there we've got 68.7 miles north to south
and 69.17 east to west so it's not a perfectly
square unit is it it's a little bit distorted
well that distortion is totally
significant because it's that distortion
that is a measure of the earth's
departure from being a perfect sphere   and it's that departure of a perfect sphere that
is very significant to us because without that
again earth's orbital stability wouldn't be would
be non-existent okay so we're going to divide this
up a little bit if we take this square degree
of of latitude north to south longitude east to
west and we look very carefully down in the
lower right hand corner you're going to see   something a little square you see that little
square that represents one minute one sixtieth
of the degree this way 1 60 of the degree this way
so that's one minute of latitude and longitude all
right we're going to take a closer look
at that and we will see that one minute
then is 6045.881 north to south 6087 east to west
which is what we expect the east west should be
a little bit longer and that's one square minute
of latitude and longitude okay now we're going to
divide each of those lengths into two we're going
to divide our square minute into 1 4 sections and
here's what i want you to notice when we do
that we take one-fourth of a square minute of   latitude and longitude look at our dimension east
to west and look at our dimension north to south
and look at these two numbers
in fact here's here's an accurate calculation
we take the 482.755 feet which is the height
and what we discover is that if we multiply that
by the number 4 43 200 which is one of our sacred
numbers that we've seen right there forty three
thousand two hundred it shows up in the vedas
in the sumerian king lists etc etc if we multiply
the height of the pyramid by that number this is
what we come out with 3949.83 miles and notice
the difference between the pyramid which i call
the standard polar radius and world grid system 72
is only 313 feet over the entire size of the earth
so we have essentially the pyramid being a scale
model of the earth the northern hemisphere at a
scale of 43 200 to 1. if we take the pyramid
enlarge it by 43 200 its height including
the sockle now becomes the polar radius of the
earth within 300 feet of our satellite surveys
then the two measures of the base are exactly the
difference between the east-west difference and
the north-south difference at a square minute at
the equator now the skeptic and the reductionist
would dismiss this and say ah it's just a
coincidence you're just playing with numbers
and i would say okay you know you can believe
what you want but it's there the numbers are   there you can take the surveys of egypt by coal
you can take the geodetic surveys i didn't make
those numbers up or i didn't fudge them and what
you discover is that when you expand it by 43
200 which you know if if the number was just some
arbitrary number but it turns out that the the
uh factor of expansion turns out to be one of the
critical sacred numbers within the ancient systems
and so here we have the pyramid now enlarged
by 43 200 times and another way to think of it
is if we go back to this diagram right
here you'll see that as the earth turns
every half second it's going to turn this far
so it means that every two seconds the earth if
you're standing on the equator in two seconds the
earth has turned 143 200 part of its total orbit
so if you're standing on the equator in
two seconds precisely the earth has turned   into a distance exactly equal to the distance
around the great the base of the great pyramid
now you can dismiss that as being
coincidence but the numbers don't lie
they're there and so when william r fix was saying
that someone somewhere thousands of years ago was
able to measure the earth with great precision
and i haven't of course elaborated upon all the
details of this i just i'm trying to give you
the overall picture of how it might have worked
referring back to our geodetic data if we look
at the various ellipsoids that give the polar
radius and then we take each of those polar radii
going from all of these ellipsoids down the clark
ellipsoid has been the one of 1880 has been
the one used in in the united states for all
non-military and non-nasa related measurements
we still use on the day-to-day basis if you
if you take a topographic map you know and you're
going out like a 7.5 quadrangle and you're going
out navigating with a topographic map put out
by the u.s geological survey they're using the
clark ellipsoid right there but you'll notice that
when we take these various polar radii lengths in
uh feet and divide them by 43 200. you can see the
numbers we get right here remember the height of
the pyramid is estimated at 482.7575 so looking
at this what you'd see on here which one would
be the closest well you notice it's come out
very very close to the to the satellite surveys
given that it's very pop and see when
you have you've got to ask yourself well   why is there a difference between this the
satellite survey of 72 and the satellite survey of
80. well if we did another one again with as high
a degree of accuracy we would discover there's
still going to be a discrepancy and the reason is
is that the earth spinning through space there are
various tidal forces working on the earth which
are constantly causing it to distort its shape by
up to two or three or four or five hundred feet
so we never would be able to get more accurate
than three or four hundred feet because the earth
itself is changing shape and if we were to measure
it every year for the next 10 years we would get
10 different numbers they'd all be very close
but they would deviate somewhat because the earth
itself there are tidal bulges you know where's the   moon relative to the earth that's going to affect
if the moon and the sun are on the same side of
the earth that will affect the shape of the earth
up to being several hundred feet measured over the
diameter diameter of the earth and so it is not a
miss to say that the pyramid enshrines a measure
of the earth that could be considered as accurate
as those determined by modern satellite surveys
that to me is a very profound insight
because it does suggest that somebody
once upon a time was able to measure the earth
size and shape with that level of precision and if
they were able to do that what's the implication
of that see that's that's the interesting part
because no primitive culture using the method
of eratosthenes in about 300 bc in greece
he measured the earth and was generally
considered to be quite accurate because   he was able to get the circumference of
the earth within about 500 miles of its
actual measured circumference by using the
methods available to the ancient greeks
you see and he was considered to be the first
to measure by by basically putting a stick in
the ground and measuring the angle of the shadow
uh on the longest day of the year over a couple
of successive years that's actually an exercise
we do in the sacred geometry class because it's
very interesting how he did that but he was
considered to be you know pretty proficient
because he was able to determine that the
uh size of the earth was the circumference   of the earth was you know 25 000 miles when
it's generally considered to be about 24 800
depending on where you measure so he was you know
maybe with maybe within 50 miles of the actual
dimension of the earth but nowhere near as close
as the pyramid would have been so again if the
even if the pyramid was built four thousand two
hundred years ago you know you gotta say who four
thousand two hundred years ago had the technology
to measure the earth with that degree of accuracy
now that we know of nobody 4 200 years ago did
or how they would have done it we don't know
but on the other hand if it turns out that
the pyramid could be much older it leads us
back to the you know going back 10 000 or 20
000 years this to me is one of those little um
oh sort of like the the little crack in the
dike that if you don't keep it plugged the whole   edifice of contemporary knowledge could get
swept away because we can't acknowledge that
somebody 10 000 or 20 000 years ago was
scientifically sophisticated that was the
days of cro-magnon man and alley-oop
living in the cave and so forth   cavemen which is a silly idea actually yes
i'm sure people did take refuge in caves
when uh things got really crazy out here
yes i think people did take refuge in caves
but see this is one of those things again that
if you accept that it's not just a coincidence   it opens up a whole can of worms that mainstream
science generally doesn't want to address
because we're the epitome of scientific evolution
right here and now right nobody before we built
satellites could have measured the earth to within
a couple of hundred feet of its actual dimensions
so given two seconds of time one forty three
thousand two hundredth part of the daily rotation
a point on the equator will travel a distance
precisely equal to the perimeter of the great
pyramids base as measured with the sockle in one
half second of time a point on the equator will
rotate a distance equal to one side of the base of
the great pyramid pyramid measured with the cycle
so here you have a time and
space measure integrated into one   the time measure comes in because it's
the span of time that the earth has moved
in two seconds the earth has turned and moved   a distance within a fraction of an inch being
the distance around the base of the great pyramid
and so the height of the great pure measured
pyramid measured with the socket was 143
200 part of the earth's polar radius so therefore
the great pyramid is a model of one hemisphere
of the earth at a scale of one to forty three
thousand two hundred so if we took the great   pyramid and we created the duplicate and turned it
upside down and put the two together base to base
that would now give us the polar diameter one more
example the parthenon to show that this geodetic
knowledge was still extant down to the time of
the building of the parthenon about 2400 years ago
this is the east facade we've all familiar with
the parthenon it's almost as well known as the   great pyramid well if we measure its base in the
manner that i'm showing here it's 100 greek feet
so how long was a greek foot a little bit
longer than our modern foot of 12 inches
before we do that let's look at the dimensions
of the parthenon based upon our american feet
that we use the east facade is 101.2957 dot
dot dot feet so if we divide that by a hundred
we get the length of the greek foot which
would have been 1.0129 etc of our american
which are actually the in british feat okay i
better write that down so we don't forget it
that's good enough right there there's the width
of the parthenon measured in our american feet and
uh also notice the latitude of athens where
the period where the parthenon is located is 37
degrees 58 minutes north and i'm going to write
that down 37 degrees 58 minutes so it's almost
almost 38 degrees north and here we have
based upon numerical and proportional
relationships augmented by extensive analysis
of ancient structures artifacts and texts
sticcini who was considered one of the preeminent
meteorologists of the 20th century he determined
various lengths of the foot he came
up with the greek foot of 1.0114064
now notice here we've got the width of the east
facade of the parthenon divided by a hundred
gives a greek foot of 1.1 1.0129 for a difference
of point zero eighteen inch in excess of the
length of the greek foot is calculated by stichini
it is acknowledged by architectural historians
that the parthenon was originally built to be 100
greek feet in width this would have made it equal
to 101.14 english feet when built now if we go
back to the length of one degree of the meridian
and we look right here at the latitude of
athens we find something very interesting
length of one degree of the meridian at the
latitude of athens is 68.962 miles or 364
121.647 feet   so if we take that number and divide it by 60
gives us the length of one minute of meridian arc
then we divide that meridian arc by 60 it gives
us one second of meridian arc and notice what
one second of meridian arc is 101.1449 feet so
one second of meridian arc at 38 degrees north
latitude given the international ellipsoid and the
clark ellipsoid you'll know here that it's exact
so in other words what we have there the total
difference in length of one second of meridian arc
at 38 degrees north latitude and the
east facade of the parthenon is .05 inch
but again that's for 38 north latitude and it's
actually at 37.58 so if we make that adjustment
of two minutes of arc south this point zero five
pretty much just disappears into nothing so what
we have is the parthenon again maybe coincidence
but here we have the parthenon being precisely one
second of arc of the earth's circumference at that
latitude that it's placed now again that implies
somebody was able to measure the earth with
incredible precision if this isn't a coincidence
and i think the burden of proof would be on
the person who tries to dismiss this as being   coincidental because the two examples i've shown
you here could be multiplied many times over
we haven't even talked about the gothic cathedrals
the fact that every gothic cathedral was built
with its own cubit and that cubit is based upon a
multiple or a subdivision of the meridian length
at the latitude that the cathedral was built so
you could take many examples of this and what
i'm suggesting here is not necessarily that the
gothic cathedral builders of 800 years ago were
able to measure the earth with that accuracy but
then again it does seem to imply that somebody was
that somebody was able to measure the earth that
maybe there has been a tradition going back to   who knows when from the building of the pyramids
coming down through the age of the greeks right
down to the building of the gothic european
gothic cathedrals 800 years ago a tradition
of very sophisticated geodetic knowledge well
again this this opens up a huge can of worms about
when people were supposed to what they knew
and when they were supposed to have learned it
so there's another dimension to this
as well and this is i'm only going to   show you a few examples out of hundreds of
possible examples i could be showing you
ancient writings semitic writings for these
and i'm coming with two examples here the
hebrew ancient writings which would be kabbalistic
writings uh the the hebrew old testament the torah
the midrash all of those and then the greek
alphabet the new testament was written in greek   all of the pythagorean neo-pythagorean literature
written into greek was it turns out both of those
languages this was prior to the advent of
the hindu arabic numeral system the hindu
arabic numeral system is when we came up with
what we now have is we have our alphabet and
we have our set of numbers and there are two
different things right we use our alphabet for
the spoken language in written language and
we use numbers for calculating in mathematics   but they're different you know we don't but prior
to the advent of the hindu arabic numeral system
in the semitic languages the same symbols that
were letters were also numbers and the key
was what you see right here called the denery
system so aleph was one bet was two gimmel
was three dalet was four hey was five wow was
six zion seven and so on down to ray sheen and
tao 200 300 and 400 yid which was considered the
seed of the hebrew alphabet had the value of tan
okay so units tens and hundreds then there
was a symbolic component to each of the for
example aleph originally was the word for an ox
and uh bait was originally the word for house
gimmo originally the word for camel and so on then
we get to the greek system and it's also daenerys
system units tens and hundreds so alpha beta
gamma delta epsilon di gamma zeta eta theta etc
one through nine then yota kappa lambda mu news
i omicron pi copper 10 through 90 and so on row
through sampi wasn't actually a written letter it
was just simply included to get the value of 900.
okay so we have the same system units
tens and hundreds so how is this employed
well here's an example here's a lethal
which was the greek word for truth and if
you add up the eta the alpha the lambda
the eta theta epsilon iota and alpha
based on the values that i just showed you the
total value is 72 and that's one of our key
sacred numbers because most of the numbers that
i showed you here are multiples of 72 36 or 72.
catabola which means conception the first
moment of creation kappa alpha tau alpha
beta omicron lambda ada take the values again
directly from the historically authenticated
table that i showed you and they add up to 432
so there you see these numbers showing up here
yerushalayim or jerusalem iota epsilon rho
omicron upsilon this would be the greek spelling
in the new testament sigma alpha lambda eta and mu
there's the values of the individual letters iota
which was tan epsilon 5 etc and
when you add those up you get 864.
again do we find that number on our list yes we do
these numbers again are showing up with redundancy
the temple of immortality honeos uh let's
see i forgot how to pronounce that uh
athanasius or naos
athanasius that's it the temple of immortality
so if we take that spelling add it up it also
is 864 and i'll work on my pronunciations for next
time ah the holy ghost tawaghian numa numa like
root of our words like
pneumatic means the holy ghost   or the holy spirit add up those the
value of those and you get 1080.
the fountain of wisdom pegasuphias also adds
to 1080. so these are just a few examples of
then i heard another great voice from heaven
saying come out my people out of her lest you   take part in her sins lest you share in her
plagues a phrase from the book of revelations
and 1296 which is half of the great year
cycle so i mean these again these these
examples can be multiplied by hundreds literally
by hundreds and this is actually a one of the sub
subdivisions of the study of kabbalah which
is the the gamatria the study of the numerical
or mathematical basis of language and what you
discover when you go into the mathematical basis
of languages the whole thing is constructed
upon the same architecture of sacred numbers
that we've been looking at here for the last hour probably of all familiar with things like here
is wisdom let him that hath understanding count
the number of the beast where is the number of a
man 603 score and six you ever heard that probably   the most famous and controversial number out of
the bible 666 well if you want to understand what
that is actually referring to you have to peel
back the outer literal representation of these
tails and look at the underlying mathematical
architecture because that's where it's concealed   and it actually turns out that the orbit orbital
velocity of the earth around the sun is 66 600
miles per hour exactly and that's one of the first
astronomical connections and then there's many
many more connections with that number that we
find occurring in sacred geometry so all of this
there's a lot of silliness and accretion stuff
that's accreted to that the belief in that number
by basically fundamentalists and superstitious
people who don't look at the underlying science
but we will take a couple of minutes
here and look at a few things   i lifted up this is from the old testament
zechariah i lifted up mine eyes again and looked
and behold a man with a measuring line in his hand
then said i withered goes thou and he said unto me
to measure jerusalem to see what is the
breath thereof and what is the length thereof
old testament prophet zechariah so here was the
beginning of his of his prophetic experience his
prophetic vision as he sees this man who's got
a measuring line in his hand and he says he's
going to go measure the holy city and when he
does see then what's the revelation it follows
the revelation is the sacred geometry that
that composes the the that is the basis of
the architecture of the holy city so the whole
revelation is really it's a geometric revelation
uh again from the book of revelations and
i looked and lo a lamb stood on the mount
of zion which to anybody whose verse knows that
that's a reference to the sign of ares the lamb
and with him a hundred and forty and four
thousand which is this number right here having
his father's name written in their
foreheads what does that mean well   it means that somebody who studies sacred
geometry eventually you've got these numbers
as such an integral part of your consciousness
in your forehead in your in your frontal lobe
your your waking consciousness that these numbers
literally become a part of the way you experience
reality and experience the world because the
numbers are all around us in the world it gives
a shape to the world it defines the periods
of time that governs the cycles of our life
and i heard a voice from heaven as the voice of
many waters and as the voice of a great thunder
and i heard the voice of harpers harping with
their harps and they sung as it were a new song
before the throne and before the four beasts
what are the four beasts the bull the lion the
eagle and the man divides the cosmic wheel into
periods of six thousand four hundred and eighty
years which i sure certainly should add because
that's an important number so there's a veiled
reference to that cycle of time six thousand
four hundred and eighty and no man could learn
that song but the hundred and forty and four
thousand which were redeemed from the earth now
when you get into kabbalistic studies you can you
can go to the english translations to kind of be
to lead you into the outer portals but if
you want to get into the inner teaching   you've got to go beyond that you've got
to go back to the original languages and
i'm not going to get too much into that but the
word redeemed is actually a very interesting word   it's talking about the redeemed of the earth 144
thousand we discovered that the word was agarazzo
from agora and it means to go to market so
basically what it's saying is that those who
achieve salvation at the at the day of
judgment are those who go out and go shopping
what well didn't that and that what george bush
told us to do after the yeah see so george bush
he had his thumb on the pulse of
but actually see why does it what's the
connection with going to market well as a place
probably the town square that should be the first
clue the square see there's your geometry uh
as a place of public resort by implication a
market of thoroughfare so the idea first is the
idea of a square because the marketplace
would be built around a square a literal
square so it it became associated with the idea
of people gathering within this square see uh
it's uh comes from well agarazzo comes from
uh yeah see here so to uh go to market by
implication to purchase especially to redeem
to redeem and it comes from this route agora
which is related to this aguero the idea of
collecting one's faculties this is the idea of
collecting within the square again right well this
thinking now about metaphorically collecting one's
faculties but also to awaken or to rouse literally
from sleep from sitting or lying from disease or
death or figuratively from obscurity or rune it
means to awake to lift up to raise up to rear up
so see all of these ideas are what you're led to
once you start going into the original kabbalistic
meanings of the language so what starts out like
go shopping go to the market means going to the
town square it means the gathering within this
square so here's the link with your geometry
but then one of the words that we we look at when
we study the the kabbalistic study of words is we
look at the original roots but then we act we look
at how did they bifurcate and how did they lead
because you can follow the evolutionary paths of
language to get back to what some of the original
meanings actually were to try to get to what
the authors of these sacred writings were really
trying to get to because you've got to remember
that all of these sacred writings have gone   through multiple layers of translation by people
who may or may not have understood the original
doctrines that were concealed in there
symbolically and mathematically also from the book
of rev oh the reference to the new song is very
interesting because uh and and i would defer later
to jeremy on this who's been studying the sacred
geometry of music but there is a phrygian mode of
of representing the octave that goes from 432
cycles per second to 864 cycles per second so this
the the reference to singing a new song suggests
to me that possibly we're talking about a change
in frequency involving life here on earth and that
those who change their consciousness accordingly
will be in harmony with the changing frequencies
and i believe that that is one of the core
teachings of this is that as earth goes through
its evolutionary journey through the galaxy
through varying geometric relationships with the
astronomical universe what is happening is that
the frequencies impinging upon the earth are
constantly going through an evolution as well
and part of understanding the ancient secrets
or methods of the master builders of old
was utilizing the sacred geometry and the
geodetic knowledge to create structures
that resonated with the earth because they were
harmonically attuned to the earth i think that's   part of what's going on trying to understand
the sacred science behind structures like the
parthenon and the great pyramid and many of the
other temples is this science of harmony of the
science of resonance and creating structures
that vibrated according to certain frequencies
and those frequencies would be attuned to the
slowly changing frequencies of the earth itself
as it goes on its cosmic journey
through through the universe   um i saw a new heaven and a new earth for the
first heaven and the first earth were passed away
and i john saw the holy city the new jerusalem
jerusalem is the 864 right 864. that's the
jerusalem coming down from god out of heaven
prepared as a bride adorned for her husband
and there came unto me one of the seven angels
saying come hither i will show thee the bride
the lamb's wife and he carried me away in
the spirit to a great and high mountain   and showed me that great city the holy
jerusalem descending out of heaven from god
having the glory of god and her light was like
unto a stone most precious it had a wall great and
high and had 12 gates and at the gates 12 angels
and names written thereon now of course those
names are mathematical keys on the east three
gates on the north three gates on the south three
gates and on the west three gates and the wall of
the city had 12 foundations and in them the names
of the 12 apostles of the lamb and he that talked
with me had a golden reed to measure the city so
here again we have this idea of the measuring of
the city because the city is the repository of the
cosmic doctrine the gates thereof in the wall
thereof and the city lieth four square and the
length is as large as the breadth and he measured
the city with the reed twelve thousand furlongs
the length and the height of it are equal and
he measured the wall thereof a hundred and forty
and four cubits according to the measure of a
man that is of the angel and i find that verse
to be particularly potent in its meaning because
first of all we have to ask the question what are
we talking about when what is the bible talking
about when it refers to angels well you know the
counterpart to angels are found in all cultures
it's just in the bible they're called angels
uh who are the messengers right from this other
domain but in other cultures they were usually
referred to as the gods and basically in the
christianization of the ancient pagan traditions
the gods were replaced by the angels but their
function within the cosmic hierarchy is identical
and so uh the fact that the
measure of a man a human
is the same as the measure of
the angel is very interesting   because it's saying that we're somehow linked
to the gods through a common system of measure
but notice the numbers 144 cubits of course you
got to ask what is a cubit and that leads us into
some interesting digressions there also the 12 000
furlongs well anybody know how much a furlong is
what is a furlong there's furlong
furlongs have almost fallen into disuse   it's a british or english unit of measurement
but it found its way into the king james bible
it was basically the british counterpart of
the greek stade which had various lengths but
basically the same length as the furlong what
was the furlock furlong where is a furlong used
today yeah who goes to the track horse racing
a furlong is 660 feet 1 8 part of a mile well
here's what's interesting about the furlong if
you multiply it by 12 to convert it to inches
you discover that the furlong is exactly
7920 inches where did we see that number
this is now a test of of your memory the
diameter of the earth remember i said the
diameter of the earth taken through the tropics
the sacred number that's representing the earth
the furlong is to the inch as the earth is to a
mile it's a proportion this is a sacred proportion
that was intentionally embodied into the units
of measurement so that we lay out a fur along
right 660 feet one inch which is derived
from our thumb the width of our thumb
right there you can check it out put your thumb
on there and you'll discover it's an inch wide   that's the digit so the thumb is to your foot
in this cosmic relationship of twelve to one
and when you pace like this is how pace was
generally considered you start from one point
put your heel against the point and
then every other step you count one two
three a thousand of those averaging 5.28 feet
gave us the mile right a thousand times 5.28
is five thousand two hundred eighty and
that was the origin of the buy the mile   is literally a mill a thousand human paces the
pace think about the pace what that is our foot
our pace our pace our foot is what anchors us
to the earth our pace is what moves us about the
face of the earth right the most fundamental
relationship we have with the earth our feet
right that ratio of pace to foot 5.28 now we have
the furlong is 12 000 of these things right 12 000
12 000 the holy city is 12 000 of these things 660
feet multiply that out you discover 7 million 920
000 feet so how big is that we'll divide
that by the number of feet in a mile
5280 and what you discover is it's precisely 1500
miles so what what would be 1500 miles in diameter
is there some some object out there
that could be 1500 miles in diameter
it's certainly described as being something
they see in the heavens right well i'll leave   this one an open-ended question for right
now but here's something that's interesting
if we take this number and divide
it into compare it to the earth
to get a sense of scale earth 7920 holy
city 1500 so we put 79 20 over 1500
and if you quickly do that calculation in your
head you'll discover that 1500 goes into 79
20 exactly 5.28 times the relationship of our foot
to our pace so here's a very strange correlation
the earth to the holy city is the same as the pace
to the foot what are they trying to say there well
one of the implications of this it follows
from this truth the truth is that we humans
are ultimately designed according to the cosmic
measure we were created in the image of god
right and god is the ultimate cosmic measure and
we being created in the image of god embody the
cosmic measures so when protagoras said man is the
measure of all things what he was implying is that
we are the ultimate yardstick for the cosmos in
fact when one looks at the scale of phenomena
from the human up to the largest macro scale
that we know of and from the human down to   the smallest micro scale we know of where are we
within that hierarchy right smack in the middle
so there's as much above us as there is below us
there's as much greater than us as there is lesser
than us and i think that's one of the implications
of this is that when we begin looking at our
sacred geometry we realize it's the ultimate
fusion of all of these phenomena on all scales
and the ultimate component or the ultimate uh the
ultimate symbol of all that fusion is we ourselves
and then of course ultimately
it's our consciousness because   like i said with the with with his name
written in our forehead what that means
is is that we when you study sacred geometry
you're literally building an edifice in your
consciousness you're building a form out of your
own the the material of your own conscious mind
that reflects this order of nature
of cosmic nature that's all about us
and that's the power and why study of sacred
geometry can now ultimately be a key to accessing
lots of other things like the kabbalah and then
the alchemy and the hermetic wisdom and the   gnostic traditions and the traditions of the vedas
and so forth there it is 12 000 furlongs the city
lieth four square forty eight thousand furlongs
at a perimeter it's also described as cubicle
twelve thousand furlongs equals seven million nine   hundred and twenty thousand feet
which equals fifteen hundred miles
the total perimeter thirty one thousand six
hundred and eighty that has a profound mystical   significance which we will save for another
time so there it is a tabulation of some of
the stuff we've covered the diameter of the earth
at 79.20 one furlong 79 20 inches the diameter of
the new jerusalem and twenty thousand feet which
is fifteen hundred miles one mile is five thousand
two hundred and eighty feet or a thousand paces
of five point two eight feet one and a half miles
is seven thousand nine hundred twenty feet and
here's the pace to the foot equals the earth to
the holy city which equals 79 20 to 1500 there's
that magic ratio of 5.28 that links the earth
to this other cosmic entity for now going unnamed
that relates to our own scale exactly as our pace
does to our foot and what you discover is that
if you're taller or shorter it doesn't matter
because it's a proportional relationship if you're
tall or your pace i have a my pace is in excess of
six feet so 5.28 you know you're going to have
a somewhat shorter but you're going to discover
that the ratio is relatively constant because as
you get taller presumably your feet get bigger
with some exceptions right i know some
little people with really big feet
and here is the hebrew cubit which is 18 inches
remember 144 cubits according to the measure of
a man that is of the angel we have the egyptian
royal cuban of 1.727 feet the wall of the city was
144 cubits if we take the 144 cubits that are the
hebrew cubits it's 216 feet or 2592 inches add one
zero on the end of that and we have the great ear
cycle 25 920 years if we express it instead in
egyptian cubits which may have been the original
intent if not implic implying that either cubit
was was legitimate 144 egyptian royal cubits of
144 times 1.727 is 248.814 move the decimal over
two points you got twenty four thousand eight
hundred and eighty one point call that miles
and there's the circumference of the earth 24 881
miles so there's all kinds of information embedded
in here but you've got to have the key to begin to
unlock it okay and then also notice that the moon
2160 miles or 17280 furlongs we set the diameter
of the moon to the diameter of the holy city
there's our 1.44 ratio so what we have here
is this redundancy over and over again we have
these same numbers recurring over and over again
in the measure of time and space both in absolute
dimensions but also in the proportional
relationships that result from comparing
these various entities of time and space as
we've learned now the diameter of the moon is
miles the diameter of the sun is 864 thousand as
it turns out if you take the diameter of the sun
and multiply it by this number right here it gives
us the distance between the earth and the sun
and if we take the diameter of the moon which
is 2160 multiply it by the same factor of 108
we discover that we now have the earth moon
distance so it's this 108 factor this 108 spacing
this proportional relationship we could express it
this way solar distance to solar diameter equals
lunar distance to lunar diameter and the value
of that proportion is the sacred number 108.
as we see embodied right here in bakheng of
cambodia from the 12th century with its 108 towers
and there are many examples of how these
numbers were incorporated into the fabric
of sacred architecture that there has been some
kind of a universal system at use in the ancient
world and these various cultural groups whether
it was the egyptians or sumerians or mayans or
the hopewellians or the megalithic builders
had access to some universal system from some
source that was outside their own cultural
context and i suggest that the source of that
goes back into deep time that takes us back beyond
the threshold of known history into the realm of
mythical history which means we're going back like
into the ice age back into the pleistocene to use
the geologic geologist term back into the to the
deep recesses of the human tenure on planet earth
whose only memory has come down to us not in the
form of recorded history but in the form of myth
and epic story and legend and so forth because as
it turns out if we in this way this is again is a
is a good topic for the sacred geometry class
when we analyze plato's description of atlantis
plato basically gave the sink the date
of the sinking of atlantis as 9 000 years
prior to solon that the egyptian the the
the athenian poet and statesman solon
did a 10-year exile in egypt and it
was solon that brought back the tale
of atlantis and presented it to the to the greeks
and solon basically made that journey around 600
bc so if you had the 9 000 years to the 600 bc
we come up with a date of about 11 600 years ago
for plato's date for this the the demise of
atlantis well it's very interesting that the date
11 600 years has been independently discovered
by geologists looking at the tempo of various
catastrophes that have occurred on earth and to
those catastrophes is where i'm now going to turn
catastrophes in the time of man the tempo of
global change what i've done here is i put
a time bar that goes from the present right here
this is us now this is today right here is may 3rd
at 4 o'clock is it 4 o'clock that's right here and
this is 150 000 years ago the reason i used 150
000 years is that some of the earliest skeletal
remains ever discovered of modern humans date
back to 150 to even to 180 000 years skeletons
that appear to be indistinguishable from a modern
skeleton which suggests that modern humans with
presumably equivalent intelligence to our own
were present on the planet at least this far
back so here we've got a 150 000 year time span
you'll notice this little red bar at the end that
red bar represents the span of recorded history
which is basically the advent of cine sumerian
uniform writing so if it turns out that there were
modern humans living through this whole span of
time why is there no history well now you got to
do is turn to these various things that i've put
on here these are events that have occurred and
i used a certain criteria for these events and
here's the criteria i used i began studying
the record of geological change climate
change environmental change and i focused on
events that could be considered catastrophic   and catastrophic to the extent that were an
event of an equivalent magnitude to occur now
it would basically end civilization as we know
it that's the criteria what would be what would
be the magnitude of an event that it would take
to terminate our modern industrial civilization
that's the criteria that i used then i began to
search through the record of all of the events
that would be of that magnitude or greater and
the events that i found so far have been entered
onto this graph and they're listed all here you
can see them and how many do we have here and this
is not complete necessarily but we have at least
one two three four five six seven eight nine 10
11 12 13 14 15 16 of them in 150 000 years so at
least 16 times in the last 150 000 years there
have been climate or environmental or geological
catastrophes powerful enough that where they occur
to occur today would essentially put us back into
the stone age but essentially if you think about
some of the small catastrophes we have seen in
the last few years from the the destruction of
new orleans to the great tsunami you know to
some of the big earthquakes that we've seen
you know new orleans is still not recovered but
you've got to imagine what would happen if an
event that was one order of magnitude greater than
katrina happened by that i mean 10 times worse
let's say that we had 10 cities decimated to the
extent of new orleans we could certainly recover
from that but it would be a major effort to do
so now what if we were talking about two orders
of magnitude let's say to put it into a rough
equivalency an event that could could cause the
decimation of a hundred major urban areas could
we recover from that questionable now let's go
three orders of magnitude and now we're talking
about the equivalent of a thousand major cities
completely decimated okay at that
level three orders of magnitude
that's what these are those are events that
essentially would be three orders of magnitude
once you begin to ponder this it
becomes apparent why there isn't   a record an extant record of what's been going on
for the whole time that we humans have been here
now at this point you probably haven't tied
this in with what we've been saying before other
than i'll point out a few things to you that
should be onset of the late wisconsin ice age
26 000 years before present remember
the great year in the processional cycle
add about 80 years to that we've got 26 000. of
course 26 000 you consider a figure plus or minus
a few centuries now you come through that cosmic
clock that i showed you right halfway to the
cusp of the age of leo twelve thousand nine
hundred years ago roughly and what happened
we have something that happened twelve thousand
nine hundred years before present on set of   the younger driest climate catastrophe
first phase of the megafauna extinctions
let's now here what i've done is i've entered
some green dots now look at what the green dots
are the green dots are basically derived
directly from the model of the great year
based upon cycles of six thousand four hundred and
eighty twelve thousand nine hundred and sixty and
then twenty 25 920 and you'll notice how high of
a correlation there is between the tempo of events
the actual events that have been derived by
scientists without any reference to this great
year model at all and the timing of these ages of
the world remember the six thousand four hundred
and eighty years that was the uh the bull the
lion the eagle and the man and according to the
traditions each of those seasons of the great year
is inaugurated by some type of a great event a
transformative event a catastrophe if you will and
what i've done here is i have developed a data set
that shows the correlation it certainly
seems from a study of this graph that these
intervals these event nodes as i call them the
susceptibility of something happening goes up
exponentially for a short period of
time here's the analogy that i have used   you're out driving along a quiet country road
you've got it on you know cruise control you're
kicking back you're listening to some tunes you're
not paying much attention you know you're talking   on your cell phone not much traffic okay now
you come up to a major highway and cars are
like this well you're crossing that intersection
and while you're crossing that intersection
now suddenly you got to put your cell
phone down and start paying attention   because if you don't you're going to get t-boned
right well obviously you've got your whole journey
and each time you cross an intersection of a major
highway you know the potential of a catastrophe
increases considerably over what it
would be while you're out there on the
lonely country road well you see our planet is
on a cosmic highway around the galaxy and we're
now beginning to understand the fine structure of
the galaxy and we realize that there is a pattern
and an order to it and there's a tempo of these
orbital revolutions there's a tempo of the galaxy
and there's a wave pattern of the earth moving
up and down above and below the galactic plane
and within that there are sub-orbital cycles as
well and we also discover that there seems to be
a tempo in the delivery of cosmic matter to the
inner solar system it doesn't seem to be random
and this is going to be beyond
the scope of today's lecture   but what i'm getting at here is that
the evidence now supports the conclusion
that the delivery of cosmic material and energy
the energy pulses that would be affecting earth
are non-random that they're on some kind of
a cosmic timetable a cosmic tempo if you will
and i think this is one of the most important
insights we get from these ancient traditions is
the measurement of cosmic time and how it relates
to us here on earth you just got to know what to
look for and where to look for it once you begin
to become aware of it and you begin to see it
you begin to realize that the cosmic fingerprints
are everywhere about us we're in fact living in
and upon the wreckage of the former worlds the
rubble of these former worlds is all around us
but we haven't had the scale of perspective to
see it and that's where we're at now i'm i'm
completely thrilled with things like the emergence
of google earth because google earth is now
allowing us to just somebody all of us to sit at
our computers and see the cosmic perspective of
earth and when you look at it from you know from
the from the extraterrestrial point of view things
begin to show up that we don't see when we're
right down here immersed on it so close that we're
like ants walking under rubble and can't can't see
what's around us but we do see that we literally
have built our own world and our own social system
on top of and out of the wreckage of former worlds
you